CAPRICORN ONE
摩羯座
Good morning, ladies and gentlemen. This is Paul Cunningham,
女士们，先生们，早上好。这是
Capricorn Control.
摩羯控制的保罗坎宁安。
The time is three minutes after six, Eastern Daylight Time.
时间是东部夏令时六点后三分钟。
Were coming up on T-minus 32 minutes. 21 seconds... mark.
T-minus 32分钟即将到来。21秒......标记。
To facilitate the broadcast media, we will precede each announcement
为方便广播媒体，我们将在每个公告之前
with a 5 seconds. tone, followed by a 1 second pause.
用5秒钟。音调，然后暂停1秒钟。
Anyone who hasn't got a press kit can pick one at the information trailer.
没有新闻资料包的人可以在信息预告片中选择一个。
At the present time, all systems are go,
目前，所有的系统都去了，
all lights are green.
所有的灯都是绿色的。
To review the morning for you, at T-minus 8 hours, 5 minutes.
在T-minus 8小时5分钟为您回顾早晨。
Launch Complex thirty-nine was cleared
发射场三十九号被清除
and we began to load liquid propellant into the launch vehicle.
，我们开始将液体推进剂装入运载火箭。
At T-minus 4 hours, 30 minutes.
在T-减去4小时30分钟。
Colonel Charles Brubaker, the Command Pilot,
指挥飞行员Charles Brubaker?
Lieutenant Colonel Peter Willis and Commander John Walker
上校，Peter Willis中校和John Walker指挥官
were awakened by Dr. Roger Burroughs, the flight surgeon.
被飞行外科医生Roger Burroughs博士唤醒。
They were given a final physical examination and pronounced all fit.
他们进行了最后的身体检查，并宣布完全适合。
The crew then had a breakfast consisting of half a grapefruit,
然后船员吃了一份早餐，包括半个葡萄柚，
a ten ounce steak,
十盎司牛排，
twelve ounces of orange juice, two eggs and toast.
十二盎司橙汁，两个鸡蛋和烤面包。
The crew is now in the gantry access arm,
现在，机组人员正站在龙门架上，
where they're preparing to enter the spacecraft.
准备进入航天器。
We're at T-minus 30 minutes. and counting.
我们在T-30分钟。并计数。
This is Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯座控制。
Good morning, gentlemen. Good morning, Horace.
先生们，早上好。早上好，霍勒斯。
Are we late?
我们晚了吗？
Traffic was terrible.
交通很糟糕。
Well, I see you're all in good spirits.
好吧，我看到你们都精神抖..
Have you done the EDS test yet? They're almost completed.
你做过EDS测试了吗？他们差不多完成了。
Do you want us to enter? In a moment.
你想让我们进入吗？一会儿。
What's up?
这是怎么回事？
I'm not very good at things like this.
我不是很擅长这样的事情。
I've known you, especially Colonel Brubaker,
我认识你，特别是布鲁贝克上校，
for some time.
已经有一段时间了。
What you're about to do today, I've spent my life.
你今天要做什么，我度过了我的生活。
I'd just like yuh to know that I feel that all I've ever worked for,
我只是想知道我觉得我曾经为之工作，
it has meaning today, and I'm very proud.
今天它有意义，我感到非常自豪。
Proud of the program
对该计划
and proud of what I've been able to contribute in some small way, and
感到自豪，并为我能够以某种小的方式做出贡献而
proud of you.
自豪，并为您感到自豪。
I'd like for you to take this Bible with you,
我希望你
from me, from all of us.
能从我这里和我们所有人一起带走这本圣经。
Why, Horace, I don't know what to say.
为什么，贺拉斯，我不知道该说些什么。
Well, try saying nothing for a change. Horace...
好吧，试着改变一下。贺...
thank you.
谢谢。
We'd be honored to take this with us.
我们很荣幸能与我们合作。
Well, gentlemen, let's go to Mars.
嗯，先生们，我们去火星吧。
This is Paul Cunningham, Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯控制的保罗坎宁安。
We're now at T-minus 21 minutes. and counting.
我们现在在T-减去21分钟。并计数。
Wives of the flight crew at the Cape will be flown back to Houston
在开普敦飞行机组的妻子将在飞行后飞回休斯敦
following launch. Good morning, Congressman Peaker.
。国会议员Peaker，早上好。
We've reserved three of the best seats for you and for General Enders,
我们为你和
right next to Vice President.
副总统旁边的General Enders预留了三个最好的座位。
Is he here yet?
他来了吗？
No, sir, he's due any moment.
不，先生，他随时都有。
Asshole probably thinks they'll delay the launch for him.
混蛋可能认为他们会推迟他的发射。
Someone should tell him this is not a bridge opening.
有人应该告诉他这不是开桥。
I hope you and Mrs. Peaker will be very comfortable.
我希望你和Peaker夫人会很舒服。
The Agency would like you to have these commemorative binoculars
机构希望您拥有这些纪念双筒望远镜，
to help you watch the launch and to remember this day.
以帮助您观看发射并记住这一天。
That's very nice. Look, Emily.
这是非常好的。看，艾米莉。
They have the date, Capricorn One emblem in gold.
他们有日期，摩羯座一个金徽。
Very nice, Hollis. I'm glad you like them.
非常好，霍利斯。我很高兴你喜欢他们。
Well, we'll need another pair for my wife.
好吧，我们需要另外一对我的妻子。
I, I beg your pardon, sir?
我请原谅，先生？
Oh, don't make a fuss, Hollis, it's all right.
哦，不要大惊小怪，霍利斯，没关系。
I said, 'we'll need another pair for my wife.'
我说，'我们的妻子需要另外一双。'?
It's really not necessary. Here, Emily, take mine.
这真的没必要。在这里，艾米丽，拿我的。
I really won't need them. No, I don't...
我真的不需要它们。不，我不...?
Congressman Peaker, there's only a limited...
国会议员Peaker，只有一个有限......?
I didn't quite hear what you said. Would you mind repeating it, please?
我听不到你说的话。请你重复一遍吗？
Oh, there's no problem. I'll get another pair right away.
哦，没问题。一世'
Very thoughtful of you.
非常考虑你。
This is Capricorn Control. We are at T-minus 15 minutes. and counting.
这是摩羯座控制。我们在T-15分钟。并计数。
All systems are go. All lights are green.
所有的系统都去了。所有灯都是绿色的。
Mission Control has reported the spacecraft is now on external power.
Mission Control报道航天器现在处于外部电源。
The launch vehicle will transfer to full internal power at T-minus 50 seconds.
运载火箭将在T-减去50秒时转移到全部内部动力。
Both Ascension and Canary tracking stations
阿森松岛和金丝雀跟踪站都
report clear reception.
报告了明确的接收情况。
The prime recovery ship, in the event of a terminated flight,
在终止飞行的情况下，主要的恢复船
will be the U.S.S. Kitty Hawk, which is located 350 nautical miles
将是位于
South, Southeast of Bermuda. This is Capricorn Control.
百慕大东南350海里的小鹰号战舰。这是摩羯座控制。
Hello, Emily. How are you?
你好，艾米莉。你好吗？
Phyllis? Hello, Hollis.
菲利斯？你好，霍利斯。
Emily, glad to see you. Hollis, how are you?
艾米丽，很高兴见到你。霍利斯，你好吗？
Very well, Mr. Vice President.
非常好，副总统先生。
How is the President today? Oh, just fine, thank you, Hollis.
今天总统怎么样？哦，很好，谢谢你，霍利斯。
He asked me to personally express his regrets at being unable to be here.
他让我亲自表达他对无法来到这里的遗憾。?华盛顿需要他注意
There were some pressing matters
一些紧迫的问题
that needed his attention in Washington.
。
Like getting re-elected?
喜欢连任？
Mr. Vice President? I hope you and Mrs. Price will be very comfortable.
副总统先生？我希望你和普莱斯夫人会很舒服。
The Agency would like you to have these commemorative binoculars
机构希望您拥有这些纪念双筒望远镜，
to help you watch the launch and to remember this day.
以帮助您观看发射并记住这一天。
Thank you. Thank you, very much.
谢谢。非常感谢你。
They're very nice. What is your name, son?
他们很善良。你叫什么名字，儿子？
Hughes, sir. Mark Hughes.
休斯，先生。马克休斯?
You learn pretty quick.
你学得很快。
You'll do all right. Thank you, sir.
你会做得很好。谢谢你，先生。
We're at T-minus 10 minutes. and counting.
我们在T-minus 10分钟。并计数。
Stage one is green.
第一阶段是绿色。
Stage two is green.
第二阶段是绿色。
Malfunction Detect System, on second panel.
故障检测系统，在第二个面板上。
Roger. M.D.S. on second panel.
罗杰。MDS在第二个面板上。
Capricorn One, we confirm T.A.R. S and M.D.S. You are green on both.
Capricorn One，我们确认TAR S和MDS你们两个都是绿色的。
You are go for Inertial Guidance and O.A.M.S. checks.
您可以选择惯性指导和OAMS检查。
Roger, Houston.
罗杰，休斯顿。
Gentlemen, we're ready to close the hatch.
先生们，我们准备关闭舱口。
Anybody wanna get out, this is your last chance.
有人想出去，这是你最后的机会。
Hey, Horace, is Mars the red one or the green one? I forgot.
嘿，霍勒斯，火星是红色的还是绿色的？我忘了。
Twenty-four billion dollars to put crazy people into space.
二十四亿美元将疯狂的人送入太空。
Keeps us off the streets.
让我们离开街头。
Colonel Brubaker has reaffirmed the completion of the EDS checks.
布鲁巴克上校重申完成了EDS检查。
Mission Control reports all systems are go,
任务控制报告所有系统都去，
all lights are green.
所有灯都是绿色。
James Kelloway, Director of the Manned Space Program,
载人航天计划主任James Kelloway此时
is in Houston at this moment.
正在休斯敦。
He is in full voice contact with the flight crew.
他与飞行机组人员保持完全的语音联系。
Landing Module O.I. shutdown.
着陆模块OI关闭。
O.I., shutdown complete.
OI，关机完成。
Capricorn One, you should have full C.M. internal power.
摩羯座一，你应该有完整的CM内部电源。
Roger, Houston. We have internal power.
罗杰，休斯顿。我们有内部力量。
Vehicle final status check.
车辆最终状态检查。
Begin status check.
开始状态检查。
T.L.R. pressure reading is 45.2 Roger, Houston.
TLR压力读数是45.2罗杰，休斯顿。
Roger, Capricorn, we copy.
罗杰，摩羯座，我们复制。
Bru, would you and your men, please, follow me?
布鲁，你和你的男人，请跟我来吗？
Hey, what the hell is this?
嘿，这到底是什么意思？
There's no time to explain. Please, follow me.
没有时间解释。请跟我来。
Are you nuts?
你疯了吗？
I said there's no time to explain! This is an emergency!
我说没时间解释了！这是紧急情况！
Please, follow me, now!
请跟我来吧！
This is Paul Cunningham, Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯控制的保罗坎宁安。
The space vehicle final checks have been completed
航天器最终检查已经完成
and the access arm is swinging into a final retract position.
，并且进入臂正在摆动到最终的缩回位置。
The destruct systems are now fully armed.
毁灭系统现在全副武装。
T.L.R. pressure reading is 45.2. Roger, Houston, 45.2.
TLR压力读数为45.2。罗杰，休斯顿，45.2。
The flight crew has completed the launch vehicle range safety checks.
机组人员已完成运载火箭安全检查。
T-minus 50 seconds. the launch vehicle will be on full internal power,
T-减去50秒。运载火箭将完全内部动力，
that begins the actual launch sequence.
开始实际发射序列。
The weather is reported good. Scattered clouds at 10.000 feet.
天气报告良好。散落在10.000英尺的云层。
All systems are go. All lights are green.
所有的系统都去了。所有灯都是绿色的。
We're at T-minus 3 minutes. 6 seconds., mark.
我们在T-3分钟。6秒。，马克。
An officer has given a go to begin the firing automatic sequence.
一名警官已开始启动射击自动序列。
From now until T-minus 50 seconds, that system is pre-set.
从现在起直到T-减去50秒，该系统已预先设定。
Initial stage thruster check is normal.
初始阶段推进器检查是正常的。
We're coming up on T-minus 1 min. 30 seconds.
我们将在T-1分钟内完成比赛。30秒。
The final range safety checks are completed.
最终的范围安全检查已完成。
The Launch Safety Officer reports all systems
启动安全官报告所有系统
are normal and we are Go at this time.
都正常，我们现在正在Go。
The launch escape tower is now fully armed.
发射逃生塔现在全副武装。
In the event of an abort,
在中止的情况下，
the tower will carry the command module away from the launch vehicle
塔架将使命令模块远离运载火箭
and will activate a system of control shift at 10.000 feet.
并且将在10.000英尺处激活控制变速系统。
The flight crew reports all guidance and navigation systems
飞行机组报告所有指导和导航系统
functioning properly.
正常运行。
The Range Safety Officer reports alternating systems are operating.
范围安全官报告交替系统正在运行。
This is Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯座控制。
It's that big tall white thing over there.
那边那个高大的白色东西。
You can't miss it.
你不能错过它。
This is Paul Cunningham, Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯控制的保罗坎宁安。
We're at T-minus 1 min. and still counting.
我们在T-1分钟。还在数着?
All systems are go. All lights are green.
所有的系统都去了。所有灯都是绿色的。
We should have launch vehicle power transfer right about now.
我们现在应该有权进行车辆动力传输。
Roger, Houston, we read nominal A.L.C.S.
罗杰，休斯顿，我们读名义ALCS?
Roger, Captain.
罗杰，船长。
We're at T-minus 30 seconds.
我们在T-减去30秒。
At the present time, all systems are go. All lights are green.
目前，所有系统都已进入。所有灯都是绿色的。
Gentlemen, we're going to be a little while.
先生们，我们将会有一段时间。
You and your men might be more comfortable in these.
你和你的男人可能会更舒服。
We're at T-minus 18 seconds. from lift-off.
我们在T-减18秒。从升空。
We're T-minus 15 seconds.
我们是T-minus 15秒。
T-minus 10 seconds., nine, eight we have ignition-
T-减10秒。，九，八我们有点火 -?
six, five -we have outboard engines-
六，五 - 我们有舷外发动机 -?
three -we have inboard engines- one, zero.
三 - 我们有舷内发动机 - 一，零。
We have a launch commit. We have a lift-off at 35 minutes. after the hour.
我们有一个启动提交。我们有35分钟的升空。过了一小时。
Roger. We are starting yaw.
罗杰。我们开始偏航了。
Roger, roll program complete.
罗杰，滚动计划完成。
Vehicles on targets and running smoothly.
车辆在目标上运行平稳。
Looking good, Capricorn.
看起来不错，摩羯座。
We're coming up on T-plus 40 seconds.
我们正在进行T + 40秒。
Staging should be in the next 30 seconds.
分段应在接下来的30秒内完成。
Outboard cutoff should be 10 seconds.
舷外截止值应为10秒。
Obeco, Capricorn. Roger, Houston.
Obeco，摩羯座。罗杰，休斯顿。
Have outboard cutoff.
有舷外截止。
Obeco at T-plus 2 minutes. 29 seconds. Going for staging.
Obeco在T加2分钟。29秒?去分期。
You are go for staging, Capricorn.
摩羯座，你要去参加舞会。
Roger, Houston. Five,
罗杰，休斯顿。五，
four, three,
四，三，
two, one.
二，一。
We reached staging.
我们达到了分期。
We copy.
我们复制。
We have separation. Confirmed. T-plus 2 minutes. 43 seconds.
我们有分离。证实。T加2分钟。43秒?
S-two ignition. We have S-two.
S-two点火。我们有S-two。
We have second stage ignition.
我们有第二阶段点火。
Stwo ignition at T-plus 2 minutes. 46 seconds.
Stwo在T加2分钟点火。46秒?
The vehicle is 47 miles down range.
该车辆的行驶里程为47英里。
Altitude: 43 miles. Velocity: 6.100 miles per hour.
海拔：43英里。速度：每小时6.100英里。
Mr. Vice President, please, give my regards to the President.
请副总统先生，向总统致以问候。
Oh, yes, I'll be very happy to do that, Hollis.
哦，是的，我很乐意这样做，霍利斯。
I, uh, hope that whatever problems he found so important
我，呃，希望他发现的任何问题如此重要，
not to be here today,
不要今天在这里，
I hope he has considerable success with them.
我希望他在这方面取得了相当大的成功。
Well, that's really very sporting of you.
嗯，这真的很适合你。
I'm sure the President will be very pleased to learn of your support.
我相信总统会很高兴得知你的支持。
The President would get considerable more of my humble support
总统会得到更多我的谦卑支持，
if he would only be a little more helpful with this program here.
如果他只对这个计划有点帮助。
Now, Hollis, you know the President is most interested in this program.
现在，霍利斯，你知道总统对这个项目最感兴趣。
I am most interested in a lot of things,
我最感兴趣的是很多东西，
including my wife's bridge game.
包括我妻子的桥牌游戏。
That is not the same as supporting something.
这与支持某些事情不同。
Hollis, there are many people who feel that we have problems here, on Earth
霍利斯，有许多人认为我们在这里遇到问题，在?我们在外太空花费数十亿美元之前
that merit our attention
，值得我们关注
before we spent billions of dollars on outer space.
。
There are a number of people who feel there are no more pressing problems
有许多人认为没有
than our declining position in world leadership.
比世界领导地位下降更紧迫的问题。
It was wonderful seeing you again, Hollis.
霍利斯再次见到你真是太好了。
The pleasure was all mine, Mr. Vice President.
副总统先生，我很高兴。
This is Paul Cunningham, Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯控制的保罗坎宁安。
You're at T-plus 2 hours, 16 minutes, into the flight.
你在飞行中的时间是2小时16分钟。
The spacecraft is now in elliptical orbit
该航天器目前处于椭圆轨道
with an apogee of 141 nautical miles
，远地点为141海里
and a perigee of 122 nautical miles.
，近地点为122海里。
Mission Control reports full voice contact with the flight crew.
Mission Control报告与机组人员进行全面的语音联系。
This is Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯座控制。
Welcome, Colonel. Would you please come with us?
欢迎，上校。你能跟我们一起去吗？
I'm not going anywhere till somebody tells us what the hell's going on.
我不会去任何地方，直到有人告诉我们到底发生了什么。
Everything will be explained to you. Bullshit, I wanna know right now!
一切都将向您解释。废话，我现在想知道！
Colonel, I know this sounds strange, we are all working for the same thing.
上校，我知道这听起来很奇怪，我们都在努力做同样的事情。
We are not your enemy.
我们不是你的敌人。
Please, wait here.
请等一下?
I suppose you're wondering why I called you up here.
我想你想知道为什么我在这里打电话给你。
Good morning.
早上好。
Hi there, Dr. Kelloway, nice to see you.
你好，Kelloway博士，很高兴见到你。
A funny thing happened on the way to Mars.
在前往火星途中发生了一件有趣的事。
Well, why don't you all sit down?
好吧，你们为什么不坐下来？
Well.
好。
Okay,
好的，
here it is.
这是。
I have to start by saying that if there was any other way,
我必须首先说，如果还有其他任何方式，
if there was even a slight chance of another alternative,
如果有其他替代方案的可能性很小，
I would give anything not to be here with you now, anything.
我会给任何不与你在一起的东西，任何东西。
Bru, how long have we known each other?
布鲁，我们彼此认识多久了？
Sixteen years, that's how long,
十六年，那是多长，
sixteen years.
十六年。
You should have seen yourself then.
那你应该见过自己。
You seemed walked out of a Wheaties box.
你似乎走出了一个Wheaties盒子。
And me, all sweaty palmed and deadly serious.
而我，所有人都满脸糊涂，致命严重。
I told everybody about this dream I had of conquering the New Frontier
我告诉大家这个我征服新边疆的梦想
and they all looked at me like I was nuts.
他们都像我坚果一样看着我。
You looked at me and said, "yes".
你看着我说，“是的”。
I remember when you told me Kay was pregnant.
我记得当你告诉我凯怀孕的时候。
We even went out and got crocked.
我们甚至出去了，并且被弄脏了。
I remember when Charles was born. We went out and got crocked again.
我记得查尔斯出生的时候。我们出去了，再次被弄脏了。
The two of us, Captain Terrific and the Mad Doctor
我们两个人，Terrific上尉和Mad Doctor?
talking about reaching the stars
谈论到达星星
and the bartender telling us maybe we'd had enough.
和调酒师告诉我们也许我们已经受够了。
Sixteen years.
十六年。
And then, Armstrong,
然后，阿姆斯特朗
stepped out on the Moon and we cried. We were so proud.
走出月球，我们哭了。我们很自豪。
Willis, you and Walker, you came in about then, both bright and talented.
威利斯，你和沃克，你当时进来了，既聪明又有才华。
Looked at me in my wash and wear shirt,
穿着我的洗衣服看着我，
carrying on this hot love affair with my slide rule
用我的滑尺继续这种热爱
and even you were caught up in what we'd done.
甚至你也被我们所做的事情所困扰。
I remember when Glenn made his first orbit in Mercury.
我记得格伦在水星的第一次轨道时。
They put up television sets in Grand Central Station,
他们在大中央车站安装了电视机
and tens of thousands of people missed their trains to watch.
，成千上万的人错过了他们的火车观看。
You know, when Apollo Seventeen landed on the Moon,
你知道，当Apollo Seventeen降落在月球上时，
people were callin' up the networks and bitchin'
人们正在召唤网络和婊子，
because reruns of I Love Lucy were cancelled.
因为我爱露西的重播被取消了。
Reruns, for Chrissake!
Reruns，为Chrissake！
I can understand if it was the new Lucy Show.
我能理解这是不是新的露西秀。
I mean, what the hell is a walk on the Moon?
我的意思是，到底是什么才能在月球上散步？
But reruns?
但重播？
Oh, Jesus!
哦，耶稣！
And then, suddenly, everybody started talking
然后，突然之间，每个人都开始谈论
about how much everything cost.
一切都花费多少。
Was it really worth twenty billion to go to another planet?
去另一个星球真的值二百亿吗？
What about cancer? What about the slums? How much does it cost?
癌症怎么样？贫民窟怎么样？它要多少钱？
How much does any dream cost? For Chrissake!
梦想花多少钱？对于Chrissake！
Since when is there an accountant for ideas?
从什么时候开始有想法的会计师？
You know who was at the launch today?
你知道谁今天在发布会吗？
Not the President,
不是总统，
the Vice President, that's who.
副总统，那是谁。
The Vice President and his plump wife.
副总统和他丰满的妻子。
The President was busy.
总统很忙。
He's not busy.
他并不忙。
he's just a little bit scared.
他有点害怕。
He sat there two months ago
两个月前他坐在那里
and put his feet up on Woodrow Wilson desk.
，站在伍德罗威尔逊办公桌前。
And he said, "Jim...
他说，“吉姆......?
make it good.
做得好。
Congress is on my back.
国会就在我的背上。
They're looking for a reason to cancel the program.
他们正在寻找取消这个计划的理由。
We can't afford another screw-up!
我们再也买不起了！
Make it good! You have my every good wish."
让它变得更好！你有我的一切好处希望。”
His every good wish. I got his sanctimonious Vice President,
他的每一个美好??愿望。我得到了他的道貌岸然的副总统，
that's what I got!
这就是我得到的！
And so there we are, after all those hopes
毕竟那些希望
and all that dreaming.
和所有梦想都在那里。
He sits there with those flags behind his chair
他坐在椅子后面有那些旗帜
and tells we can't afford a screw-up.
，告诉我们买不起搞砸了。
And guess what? We had a screw-up.
你猜怎么着？我们搞砸了。
A first-class, bonafide, made-in-America screw-up!
一流的，真实的，美国制造的搞砸！
The nice people from Con-Amalgamate delivered a life-support system
来自Con-Amalgamate的优秀人才提供了
cheap enough so they could make a profit on the deal.
足够便宜的生命支持系统，以便他们能够在交易中获利。
Works out fine for everybody. Con-Amalgamate makes money,
对每个人都很好。Con-Amalgamate赚钱，
we have our life-support system,
我们有生命支持系统，
everything is peachy!
一切都很好！
Except they made a little bit too much profit.
除了他们赚了一点点利润。
We found out two months ago, it won't work.
我们两个月前发现，它不会起作用。
You guys would all be dead in three weeks. It's as simple as that.
你们三个星期都会死的。就这么简单。
So all I have to do is report that and scrub the mission.
因此，我所要做的就是报告并完成任务。
Congress has its excuse,
国会有借口，
the President still has his desk and we have no more program.
总统仍然有他的办公桌，我们没有更多的计划。
What's sixteen years? An actual drop in the bucket!
什么是十六年？桶中的实际下降！
All right, that's the end of the speech. Now, we're getting
好的，这就是演讲的结束。现在，我们正在
to what they call the moment of the truth.
实现他们所谓的真理时刻。
Come with me,
跟我来，
I wanna show you something.
我想给你看点什么。
Roger, Houston. TMI burn time will be 5 minutes. 45 seconds.
罗杰，休斯顿。TMI燃烧时间为5分钟。45秒?
Roger, Capricorn.
罗杰，摩羯座。
Delta vapor burn time 3.3 seconds.
Delta蒸汽燃烧时间为3.3秒。
There's a door here. I'm gonna open it and walk into another area.
这里有一扇门。我打开它然后走进另一个区域。
If you follow me, you'll see a bit more. I'll answer some questions and...
如果你跟着我，你会看到更多。我会回答一些问题......
and we're going to...
我们要去...?
Why don't you just follow me?
你为什么不跟着我？
You don't really think you're gonna get away with this?
你真的不认为你会逃脱这个吗？
Well, I don't know, it's a chance.
好吧，我不知道，这是一个机会。
Maybe it's not a very good one, but it's a chance.
也许这不是一个很好的，但这是一个机会。
Who knows about this? Almost nobody.
谁知道这件事？几乎没有人。
Houston is monitoring the actual flight.
休斯顿正在监控实际飞行。
All the telemetry is coming from the Command Module,
所有遥测都来自命令模块，
so are your voices and medical data.
您的声音和医疗数据也是如此。
We recorded everything from the practice simulations.
我们记录了练习模拟中的所有内容。
They don't know.
他们不知道。
All we need from you is the actual television transmissions
我们所需要的只是
during the flight and the Mars landing, that's all.
在飞行和火星着陆期间的实际电视传输，就是这样。
Just the television transmissions.
只是电视传输。
That's all?
就这样？
Just the television transmissions.
只是电视传输。
We inserted a change in the onboard computer,
我们在机载计算机上插入了一个变化，
so the spacecraft will land two hundred miles off target
因此航天器
when it returns to Earth.
返回地球时将离目标200英里。
You'll be flown to an island near that point.
你将飞到那个附近的岛屿。
From there you'll be transferred to a helicopter.
从那里你将被转移到直升机。
The helicopter will fly you to the space capsule and you'll be put inside.
直升机会飞到太空舱，你会被放进去。
It'll take the Recovery Forces a minimum of an hour and a half
恢复力量需要至少一个半小时
to reach the splashdown site.
才能到达飞溅地点。
By then, you'll be inside the capsule.
到那时，你将进入胶囊。
When the prime recovery carrier arrives,
当主要恢复载体到达时，
they'll find you inside the capsule and take you out of the spacecraft.
他们会在胶囊内找到你并带你离开宇宙飞船。
You've thought of everything.
你已经想到了一切。
I don't know. I hope so.
我不知道。希望如此。
Of course, you're sure we'll go along, right?
当然，你确定我们会继续，对吗？
No, I'm not.
没有，
What if we say no?
如果我们说不，该怎么办？
I don't know.
我不知道。
Don't say no.
不要说不。
When does Allen Funt come running in and tell us we're on Candid Camera?
艾伦·福特什么时候跑来跑去告诉我们我们在坦率相机上？
Jesus! you think I like this?
耶稣！你觉得我喜欢这个吗？
You think I really believe I'm standing here in this craziness
你觉得我真的相信我站在这里疯狂地
telling you about patching and tape recordings
告诉你有关补丁和录音带
and telemetry and an island two hundred miles from the target zone?
和遥测以及离目标区200英里的岛屿吗？
I don't, I don't know what the hell I'm doing, either!
我不知道，我也不知道我到底在做什么！
I just case so Goddamn much, I think it's worth it.
我只是这么多，我认为这是值得的。
I'm not even sure of that. I just think it.
我甚至都不确定。我只是想到了。
I think I'm gonna throw up.
我想我会呕吐。
Well, that'll solve everything.
那么，这将解决所有问题。
Well, what's this all gonna solve?
嗯，这一切都会解决么？
It'll keep something alive that shouldn't die!
它会保留一些不应该死的东西！
Before you all begin to moralize, you take a look around.
在你们开始道德化之前，你们去看看。
You look at what we've done and how much more we can do.
你看看我们做了什么，以及我们能做多少。
You look at what we've meant to this country.
你看看我们对这个国家的意义。
Nobody gives a crap about anything any more.
没有人再给出任何废话了。
People close their garages, and triple lock their doors,
人们关闭他们的车库，三重锁定他们的门，
they hide under the beds, they even, they're even afraid
他们躲在床下，他们甚至，他们甚至害怕
to turn on their television sets for fear of what they might find out
打开他们的电视机，因为害怕他们可能
in the evening news.
在晚间新闻中发现。
There's nothing more to believe in.
没有什么可以相信的了。
Now, you wanna blow this whole thing wide open?
现在，你想把整个事情吹得一团糟吗？
God knows what it might do to everybody.
上帝知道它可能会对每个人做些什么。
I'm sorry. I'm so Goddamn sorry. I just don't know what else to do.
对不起。我很抱歉。我只是不知道还能做什么。
I'm hanging on by my fingernails, just like everybody else.
就像其他人一样，我的指甲挂在上面。
Go on, you, you wanna be the ones
继续，你，你想成为
who give everyone another reason to give up?
那些给每个人放弃另一个理由的人吗？
Go on!
继续！
This is really wonderful.
这太棒了。
We go along with you
我们与你
and lie our asses off, and the world of truth and ideals is...
同行，谎言我们的驴子，真理和理想的世界......?
protected.
受到保护。
But we don't wanna take part in some giant ripe-off of yours
但是，我们不想参与你们的一些巨大的成熟，
and some how or other we're managing to ruin the country.
以及一些我们如何破坏这个国家。
You're pretty good, Jim. I'll give you that.
吉姆，你很好。我会告诉你的。
Now, now, now, you're twisting my words.
现在，现在，现在，你正在扭曲我的话语。
Don't sell yourself short! Don't sell the program short!
不要卖空自己！不要卖短程序！
Don't oversell it. I'm not so sure that cancelling a flight
不要夸大它。我不太确定取消航班
or cutting off appropriations means America folds up.
或切断拨款意味着美国会放弃。
It's not as simple as that and you know it!
它不是那么简单，你知道！
I don't know it.
我不喜欢
If the only way to keep something alive
如果保持活力的唯一方法
is to become everything I hate,
就是成为我讨厌的一切，
I don't know if it's worth keeping it alive.
我不知道是否值得让它保持活力。
Please, Bru, don't talk like that.
请，布鲁，不要这样说。
What the hell's the matter with you, 'Please, Bru, don't talk like that?'
你到底怎么回事，'拜托，布鲁，不要那样说话吗？'?
I don't think this is right! All the rest is bullshit!
我不认为这是对的！其余的都是胡说八道！
You have to help!
你得帮忙！
What do you mean I have to? You have to help!
你是什??么意思我必须这样做？你得帮忙！
And what if I don't?
如果我不这样做怎么办？
Please, don't put me in a corner.
拜托，不要把我放在角落里。
You're crazy.
你疯了。
You know that? You are crazy! You've got us in the middle of this nuthouse!
你知道的？你疯了！你让我们在这个坚果屋的中间！
and you don't wanna be put in a corner?
而且你不想被放在角落里？
Your families!
你的家人！
What about our families? Please, you have to help!
我们的家人呢？拜托，你得帮忙！
What about our families? You have to help!
我们的家人呢？你得帮忙！
Shit, this thing is outta my hands!
妈的，这东西不在我的手里！
You think it's all a couple of looney scientists?
你认为这是几个疯子科学家吗？
It's not! It's bigger!
不是！它更大！
There are people out there, forces out there,
有人在那里，力量在那里，
who have a lot to lose! They are grown-ups!
谁有很多损失！他们是成年人！
It's gotten too big! It's in the hands of grown-ups!
它变得太大了！它掌握在成年人手中！
What about our families?
我们的家人呢？
They are flying back from the Cape to Houston! They are all on the plane!
他们从开普敦飞回休斯敦！他们都在飞机上！
Naw, you're not serious.
Naw，你不认真。
Please, Bru, don't make me! You son-of-a-bitch, tell me!
请，布鲁，不要让我！你这个婊子，告诉我！
They're on the plane together! You want it in writing?
他们一起在飞机上！你想要写作吗？
There's a device! It's on the plane!
有一个设备！它在飞机上！
There's some people! If I don't give the 'all clear' signal they'll explode it!
有一些人！如果我不给出“全部清晰”的信号，它们就会爆炸！
Don't you understand? It doesn't have to be like this!
你不明白吗？它没有
You have to help!
你得帮忙！
It's gotten outta control! It's too big!
它已经失控了！这个太大了！
You wouldn't.
你不会。
Tell me you wouldn't.
告诉我你不会。
I, I can't tell you that, Bru.
我，我不能告诉你，布鲁。
This coffee is horrible.
这咖啡太可怕了。
It's not that bad. It is. It's that bad.
没那么糟糕。它是。这很糟糕。
Don't drink it.
不要喝它。
I'm always unwrapping things.
我总是在打开东西。
I wake up and take the cellophane off the drink glass.
我醒来，把玻璃纸从玻璃杯上取下来。
The soaps in the Holiday Inn wrapper,
Holiday Inn包装中的肥皂，
even the toilet has a paper band on it with a nice little note from the hotel
甚至厕所都有一个纸带，酒店附有一个漂亮的小纸条，
saying they put the band on the toilet for my protection.
说他们把乐队放在马桶上以保护我。
I'm afraid that if I stay in bed too long,
我担心，如果我长时间待在床上，
the maid walks in the room and surround me and
女仆走进房间，围着我，
the bread spread with a paper band.
面包用纸带散开。
I don't mind.
我不介意。
You wait. After a while you won't know what city you are in.
你等待。过了一会你就不知道你在哪个城市。
I defy anyone to tell me the difference between the Holiday Inn in Houston
我无视任何人告诉我休斯顿
and the Holiday Inn in Cincinnati. The rooms are the same.
假日酒店和辛辛那提假日酒店之间的区别。房间是一样的。
The music in the elevators is the same,
电梯里的音乐是一样的，
even the ladies with too much makeup in the coffee shop are the same.
即使是咖啡店化妆太多的女士也一样。
You never know where you are until after breakfast,
直到早餐后，
when you read the paper. I don't mind it.
当你读到报纸时，你才知道自己身在何处。我不介意。
Well, I don't mind it that much, either.
好吧，我也不介意那么多。
It's just that I would like it all to be with someone I care for,
只是我希望与我关心的
someone I could share it with.
人，我可以分享的人在一起。
Bullshit. You're so damn cynical.
废话。你是如此愤世嫉俗。
I'm not cynical. It's just that your act could use a little polish.
我不是愤世嫉俗。只是你的行为可以使用一点点润色。
What do you mean by that? Liz Haller, for starter.
你是什??么意思？Liz Haller，首发。
It was at the California Primary?
那是在加州小学？
I believe you used the one about both witnessing to the unfolding of history.
我相信你用的是一个见证历史展现的人。
You've got to admit it's better than soap wrappers.
你必须承认它比肥皂包装更好。
You think all I wanna do is jump you.
你认为我想做的就是跳你。
Yes.
是。
You wouldn't know sincerity if it ran over you.
如果它碾过你，你就不会知道真诚。
Not if you were driving it. I'm glad I'm not like you.
如果你是在开车的话。我很高兴我不喜欢你。
I have better legs.
我有更好的腿。
Okay, I give up.
好的，我放弃了。
Don't give up so easily, just change your approach.
不要轻易放弃，只需改变你的方法。
What approach would you like?
你想要什么方法？
How about something like, uh, 'I would like to jump you'?
怎么样的，呃，'我想跳你'？
Think that would work?
认为这会奏效吗？
It has more chance than wanting to share a life together.
它比想要共同分享生活的机会更多。
I would like to jump you. Go jump yourself.
我想跳你。去跳吧。
I'm sorry that you had to wait outside the house all day like this.
对不起，你必须像这样整天在屋外等。
There is not much that I can say except that
除了
I'm very excited and proud.
我非常兴奋和自豪之外，我所说的并不多。
Everything seems to be going smoothly.
一切似乎都很顺利。
Dr. Kelloway called to say that Bru and the crew were in excellent spirits.
Kelloway博士打电话说Bru和船员精神很好。
How has all this disrupted your family routine?
这一切如何扰乱了你的家庭日常生活？
Terrific question. Shove it!
太棒的问题。推它！
Well, the children will continue to go to school
那么，孩子们将继续上学
and we'll try to maintain a normal existence.
，我们将努力保持正常生活。
I suppose that's all that I have to say.
我想这就是我要说的一切。
Thank you all for coming.
谢谢大家的光临。
Uh, I just came out to say hello and go back inside now.
呃，我刚出来打招呼然后回到里面。
Thank you. Goodbye.
谢谢。再见。
Dr. Bergen?
卑尔根博士？
Yes, Elliot? I wonder if I could talk to you
是的，艾略特？我想知道我是否可以跟你说话
for a moment. What is it?
一会儿。它是什么？
Well, there's somethin'... I have a problem, sir.
嗯，有一些事情......我有一个问题，先生。
Oh, are you feeling all right? Oh, yes, sir. It's the readout.
哦，你感觉还好吗？哦，是的，先生。这是读数。
What about the readout?
读数怎么样？
Well, I, I just can't figure something out.
好吧，我，我只是想不出办法。
Well, perhaps I can be of some help. Well, I hope so.
好吧，也许我可以提供一些帮助。好吧，我希望如此。
See, I ran a check on the transmission, on my own on the signals.
看，我自己检查了传输信号。
On your own? Yes, sir.
靠你自己？是的先生。
I like your dedication. The readout...
我喜欢你的奉献精神。读数......?
The television signals are coming in ahead of the spacecraft signals.
电视信号在航天器信号之前进入。
It's like they're closer or something.
这就像他们更近或什么的。
Oh, that's not possible. There must be some malfunction in your equipment.
哦，那是不可能的。您的设备必须有一些故障。
Well, I don't think so, Dr. Bergen. You see, I doubled checked that console.
嗯，我不这么认为，卑尔根博士。你看，我加倍检查了控制台。
Which console are you on? Thirty-six, sir.
你在哪个控制台？三十六岁，先生。
Well, that's the answer.
嗯，这就是答案。
We've been having problems with the circuitry on thirty-six.
我们三十六年来一直遇到电路问题。
We've had trouble with it before. I'll make sure it's repaired and,
我们以前遇到过麻烦。我会确保它已经修好了，
thank you for showing me the problem. You have initiative, I like that.
谢谢你告诉我这个问题。你有主动性，我喜欢这样。
This is Paul Cunningham. Capricorn Control.
这是保罗坎宁安。摩羯座控制。
We are at T-plus one 131 days, 4 hours, 15 minutes, into the flight.
我们在飞行中一个131天，4小时15分钟的T加号。
5 minutes. from landing.
5分钟。从登陆。
The wives of the flight crew arrived at Mission
飞行机组的妻子
Control at 2.31 Eastern Daylight Time.
于东部夏令时间凌晨2点31分抵达任务控制中心。
In just a few minutes
在短短几分钟内，
we should be receiving a signal from the spacecraft.
我们应该收到航天器发出的信号。
It's important to know that it takes 21 minutes. for the signal
知道这需要21分钟，这很重要。
from Mars to reach Earth.
从火星到达地球的信号。
We have no way of communicating with Capricorn One
我们无法与Capricorn One交流，
and what we will see actually happened 21 minutes. ago.
我们将看到实际发生的事情是21分钟。前。
This is Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯座控制。
We're getting something now.
我们现在有所收获。
We are changing to a secondary frequency.
我们正在改变次要频率。
Houston, this is Capricorn One.
休斯顿，这是摩羯座之一。
CM-LM separation was normal.
CM-LM分离正常。
I have CM visual contact through port window.
我通过端口窗口进行CM视觉联系。
Delta-V burn time: 3.3 seconds.
Delta-V燃烧时间：3.3秒。
3.3 seconds. burn is correct.
3.3秒?烧伤是正确的。
We should be hearing from the CM... soon.
我们应该很快听到CM的消息。
Houston, this is Capricorn CM. Just wait.
休斯顿，这是摩羯座CM。等一下?
I see the LM.
我看到了LM。
5 minutes. after the landing, that asshole Price'll be callin'
5分钟。在降落之后，那个混蛋价格会打电话
to tell me how pleased the President is.
告诉我总统是多么高兴。
If our data is correct, their altitude is 2.2 miles,
如果我们的数据是正确的，它们的高度是2.2英里，
pitch angle, 20 degrees.
俯仰角，20度。
Vertical descent 44.6 feet per second.
垂直下降44.6英尺每秒。
We have passed Low Gate. Altitude: 950 feet. Looking good.
我们通过了Low Gate。海拔：950英尺。看起来不错。
15 seconds. 15 seconds.
15秒?15秒?
10 seconds.
10秒?
Nine...
九......?
eight...
八......?
seven...
七......?
six...
六......?
five...
五......?
four...
四......?
three...
三......?
two...
二......?
one...
一......?
zero.
零。
Houston, this is Capricorn One.
休斯顿，这是摩羯座之一。
We have landed.
我们降落了。
Yes? Vice President Price on the line.
是？副总统普莱斯就行了。
Hello.
你好。
Hello, Mr. Vice President.
你好，副总统先生。
Yes, it's wonderful, isn't it?
是的，这太好了，不是吗？
Proud moment for all Americans.
所有美国人都感到骄傲。
You can tell the President that's very gracious of him.
你可以告诉总统他非常亲切。
I appreciate it, I really do.
我很感激，我真的很喜欢。
Thank you.
谢谢。
And my very best to your lovely wife.
而且我对你可爱的妻子最好。
Yes.
是。
Goodbye.
再见。
Asshole.
混蛋。
Dr., I wonder if I can speak to you for a moment.
博士，我想知道我能不能跟你说话。
Certainly, what seems to be the problem?
当然，这似乎是什么问题？
Well, I just can't figure something out, sir.
先生，我只是无法解决问题。
What is that?
那是什么？
Well, I'm not exactly sure, but it's the readout.
嗯，我不太确定，但这是读数。
I told Dr. Bergen about it a long time and he said it was in the console.
我告诉卑尔根博士很久了，他说这是在控制台里。
I'd like you to take a look at it.
我希望你看看它。
Well, what console are you on? Telemetry, sir, thirty-six.
嗯，你在用什么控制台？遥测，先生，三十六岁。
Oh, yes, Dr. Bergen told me about that. We had that console repaired.
哦，是的，卑尔根博士告诉了我这件事。我们修理了控制台。
I know, sir, it's just...
我知道，先生，这只是...?
I keep on having the same readouts.
我继续使用相同的读数。
Well, what readout?
那么，什么读数？
Well, sir, I ran a program on my own just to check something
好吧，先生，我自己运行一个程序只是为了检查一些东西
and the readout is different.
而且读数不同。
You ran your own program?
你运行自己的程序？
Yes, sir,
是的，先生，
and...
......?
I don't think it's the console.
我不认为这是控制台。
Well, we'll have it shut down and I'll see that it's serviced.
好吧，我们将它关闭，我会看到它已经得到了服务。
Thank you, Elliot, for bringing the matter to my attention.
感谢Elliot将此事提请我注意。
You're welcome, sir.
先生，欢迎您。
This is Paul Cunningham, Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯控制的保罗坎宁安。
The Flight Director advises that the LM crew has been given a Go
飞行指导员建议LM机组人员
for the first D VA on the Martian surface.
在火星表面上获得第一个D VA。
Because the time delay would make a conversation impossible,
由于时间延迟会使谈话无法进行，
the crew has taken a prerecorded message
因此工作人员已经
from the President with them.
从总统那里收到了预先录制的信息。
This is Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯座控制。
Houston, we're activating the camera.
休斯顿，我们正在激活相机。
Roger, Capricorn.
罗杰，摩羯座。
Houston, you should have a picture now.
休斯顿，你现在应该有一张照片。
We have a pretty good picture now. Houston, I am outta the hatch.
我们现在有一张很好的照片。休斯顿，我离开了。
I am on the ladder.
我在梯子上。
Houston, the suit is functional.
休斯顿，这套西装很实用。
The ladder is steady. I am three steps from the bottom.
梯子稳定。我从底部走三步。
I'm two steps from the bottom.
我距离底部两步之遥。
Houston, I'm on the bottom step.
休斯顿，我迈出了一步。
Houston, I am gonna set foot on the surface.
休斯顿，我要踏上表面。
Ready slow-mo.
准备好慢动作。
I take this step
我
in the journey of peace
在
for all mankind.
全人类的和平之旅中迈出了这一步。
Take slow-mo!
慢慢来吧！
Houston, I am on the surface.
休斯顿，我表面上看。
Roger, Capricorn. We copy.
罗杰，摩羯座。我们复制。
I am starting to walk now.
我现在开始走路了。
Houston, the surface is solid. Visibility is good.
休斯顿，表面很坚固。可见性很好。
I'm walking toward the camera now.
我现在走向相机。
The footing is solid.
基础是坚实的。
Surface seems powdery.
表面看起来很粉状。
I am picking up the camera now.
我现在正拿起相机。
I have the camera.
我有相机。
The picture will get shaky for a while.
这张照片会有一段时间不稳定。
The footing is good.
基础很好。
Houston, I am setting the camera down now.
休斯顿，我现在正在设置相机。
The rocks seem very porous.
岩石似乎非常多孔。
Houston, I am outside the hatch.
休斯顿，我在舱口外。
Houston, I am on the ladder.
休斯顿，我在梯子上。
Ready slow-mo.
准备好慢动作。
Houston, I'm stepping onto the surface
休斯顿，我正踩到水面上
Take slow-mo!
慢慢走！
Houston, I am on the surface.
休斯顿，我表面上看。
We are going to set the flag on the surface.
我们将在表面上设置标志。
We do not claim this planet in the name of America.
我们不以美国的名义声称这个星球。
We claim it in the name of all the the people of the planet Earth.
我们以地球上所有人的名义声称它。
We hope that our visit will increase the understanding
我们希望这次访问能增进
of the human race.
对人类的了解。
Walker should be activating the tape soon
Walker应该使用
with the prerecorded message from the President.
总统预先录制的消息尽快激活录音带。
Houston, I am starting the tape.
休斯顿，我正在开始录音。
"To the men of Capricorn One."
“对于摩羯座一号的人来说。?
"
I bring you greetings
from your fellow Americans"
”“我带给你们美国同胞的问候?
"
and all the citizens of the world."
”和“世界上所有的公民。
You are so far away.
”你是如此遥远。
It takes light more than 20 min. to reach you from here.
它需要超过20分钟的光。从这里到达你。
One could say not only light,
人们不仅可以说光，
one could say time.
也可以说时间。
You are in another time from us,
你是我们
the future.
未来的另一个时代。
We will never be the same,
我们永远不会是一样的，
for this moment
在这个时刻，
more than any moment in our history,
比我们历史上任何时刻
has made all of the people in the world realize
都更让世界上的所有人都意识到了
that we are part of the planet,
我们是地球的
that is part of the system,
一部分，
that is part of the Universe.
这是系统的一部分，也是宇宙的一部分。
We are a small energetic species,
我们是一个小的精力充沛的物种，
capable of pettiness, yet capable of brilliance.
能够小心，但能够有光彩。
We know how bad we can be,
我们知道我们有多糟糕，
now you, the men of Capricorn One,
现在你们，摩羯座一号的人，?通过告诉我们我们能达到多高，向我们
have shown us how wonderful we can be
展示了我们多么美妙
by showing us how high we can reach.
。
You have crossed the last great frontier
你越过了最后一个伟大的边界
and you have shown us what we are:
，你已经告诉我们我们是什么：
people.
人。?然而，
Of different colors and religions and ideologies,
不同的颜色，宗教和意识形态
however, a single people.
，一个人。
You are the basic truth in us.
你是我们的基本事实。
You are the reality.
你是现实。
We will never let you down
我们绝不会让你失望
and we will always be grateful."
，我们将永远感激不尽。“
I have decided after a careful deliberation
我经过仔细考虑
and a painful soul-searching to give you an opportunity
和痛苦的反省后决定让你有机会
to win your 50 dollars back. I don't feel like playing.
赢回50美元。我不喜欢玩。
Eight ball, five dollars a game. I don't feel like it.
八球，一场比赛五美元。我不喜欢它。
10 dollars. I'm serious.
10美元。我是认真的。
So am I. I'll even let you break. Can a person be more serious?
我也是。我甚至会让你休息。一个人可以更严肃吗？
You're drunk.
你醉了。
I knew there was a reason I was feeling this good.
我知道有一个原因让我感觉很好。
I need a drink.
我需要一杯饮料。
Underneath that wash and wear shirt, you have some heart.
在洗衣服下面，你有一些心脏。
It may be sanforized, but it's a heart.
它可能是三得利的，但它是一颗心。
Mike?
麦克风？
You said I break. I musta been drunk.
你说我休息了。我一定是喝醉了。
Hard day at the office, dear? I don't wanna talk about it.
办公室辛苦了，亲爱的？我不想谈论它。
Did you break your slide rule? I'm not really sure.
你打破了你的幻灯片吗？我不太确定。
I ran a check on my own transmissions signals.
我对自己的传输信号进行了检查。
The numbers came up screwy, so I told Dr. Bergen about it.
数字变得棘手，所以我告诉卑尔根博士。
It was like he was pissed at me for running a check.
就像他因为检查我而生气。
He said it must be a console malfunctioning.
他说它一定是控制台故障。
So I told Dr. Kelloway about it and he said the same thing.
所以我告诉Kelloway博士，他说了同样的话。
Big deal. What did you expect, a merit badge?
很重要。你有什么期望，一个功绩徽章？
I guess so. They must know what they're doing.
大概吧。他们必须知道他们在做什么。
Those numbers couldn't have been right anyway. No way.
无论如何，这些数字不可能是正确的。没门。
If you know the numbers couldn't have been right,
如果你知道数字不对，
why are you so upset?
你为什么这么难过？
It was the way they reacted. No double check or anything.
这是他们的反应方式。没有仔细检查或任何东西。
They looked at me like I was a kid and offered me a cookie.
他们像我小时候一样看着我，给了我一个饼干。
What were the numbers? I have to admit it is ridiculous.
这些数字是多少？我不得不承认这很荒谬。
Good, let's play pool.
好，让我们一起玩吧。
Those signals couldn't have come from 300 miles.
那些信号不可能来自300英里。
Which signals?
哪个信号？
The television transmission.
电视传输。
I think I just sobered up. Would you tell me what you just told me again?
我想我刚刚清醒过来。你能告诉我你刚才告诉我的事吗？
Hey, Caulfield, telephone.
嘿，考尔菲尔德，电话。
Hello?
你好？
yes, this is Caulfield.
是的，这是Caulfield。
What?
什么？
I'm sorry, you'll have to speak more clearly.
对不起，你得说得更清楚了。
I think we have a bad connection or something. I can't hear you.
我认为我们的联系很糟糕。我听不到你的声音。
Who?
谁？
I don't understand what you want.
我不明白你想要什么。
Look, if you call the assignment desk,
看，如果你打电话给作业台，
they'll be glad to send someone over to cover that for you.
他们会很高兴派人去为你报道。
Yes, ask for the assignment desk.
是的，请求分配台。
Assignment. That's right.
分配。那就对了。
You're welcome.
别客气。
Anybody hungry?
有人饿吗？
No.
没有。
Oh, the marvels of American science.
哦，美国科学的奇迹。
Here we are, millions of miles from the Earth
我们在这里距离地球数百万英里
and we can still send out for a pizza.
，我们仍然可以发送披萨。
I'm not gonna do it.
我不会这样做的。
Not gonna do what?
不会做什么？
Tomorrow, I'm not gonna sit in this thing
明天，我不会坐在这件事情上
and talk to my wife and tell her everything is going fine.
与我的妻子交谈并告诉她一切都很顺利。
I'm not gonna do it.
我不会这样做的。
I tried.
我试过了。
I got two little kids with big bright eyes.
我有两个小聪明的孩子。
And I used to tell them their daddy was gonna make them proud of him
而且我常常告诉他们他们的爸爸会让他们
like he was of them.
像他一样为他们感到骄傲。
And now I gotta go home,
现在我得回家了，
I gotta kiss them and gotta look in their eyes
我要吻他们，然后看着他们的眼睛
and tell them I really did this?
告诉他们我真的这么做了吗？
I don't know. Maybe that's better that telling them I really didn't do it.
我不知道。也许告诉他们我真的没有这样做更好。
I wish I knew what was right. I really don't.
我希望我知道什么是对的。我真的没有。
We've been sitting around here for months, telling their lies for them.
我们几个月来一直坐在这里，告诉他们的谎言。
And I don't wanna do it any more.
我不想再这样做了。
Okay, so we go and blow the whole thing tomorrow, on national TV,
好的，所以我们明天去国家电视台播放整个事情，
then what have we done?
然后我们做了什么？
We'd screw up a lotta people's dinner. We've already screwed ourselves.
我们搞砸了很多人的晚餐。我们已经搞砸了自己。
Okay, so what do we accomplish by screwing everybody else?
好吧，那么我们通过搞砸别人怎么办？
He's got a point there, you know. We went along with this for you.
你知道，他在那里有一个观点。我们为你这样做了。
You and our families.
你和我们的家人。
Now you wanna go out in some terrific blaze of glory?
现在你想走出一些极好的荣耀之火？
And we get pulverized in the process?
我们在这个过程中被粉碎了吗？
And our families?
还有我们的家人？
What about our families? I know!
我们的家人呢？我知道！
I know.
我知道。
Shit!
拉屎！
That's the best thing I've heard anybody say in three weeks.
这是我在三周内听到的最好的事情。
What's the best thing? Shit.
什么是最好的？拉屎。
I just don't think I can do it.
我只是觉得我不能这样做。
Get me Dr. Kelloway.
给我Kelloway博士。
Why, all of a sudden, are we standing up for the bad guys
突然之间，为什么我们为坏人挺身而出
and you're on the side of truth and justice?
，你站在真理和正义的一边？
We may have a problem with Brubaker tomorrow.
明天我们可能会遇到布鲁贝克的问题。
I wish I had the words. Damn the words, Bru!
我希望我有这些话。该死的话，布鲁！
These people... they're capable of anything.
这些人......他们有能力做任何事情。
And we got our families out there.
我们把我们的家人带到了那里。
Now, we're in this thing and I think we're in too deep to stop now.
现在，我们处在这个问题上，我认为现在我们已经太深入了。
No one of us is gonna decide.
我们中没有人会决定。
It's got to be all of us.
它必须是我们所有人。
Operator, I'm trying a number now for over an hour and it's busy.
接线员，我现在正在尝试一个号码超过一个小时而且很忙。
Would you kindly check to see if it's out of order?
你能好好检查一下吗？
I know you don't do that.
我知道你不这样做。
Yes, it's an emergency.
是的，这是紧急情况。
Thank you. 8733657.
谢谢。8733657.?
No, 3657, Mr. Elliot Whitter.
不，3657，Elliot Whitter先生。
Out of order?
出故障？
Thank you very much, operator.
非常感谢，运营商。
This is Paul Cunningham, Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯控制的保罗坎宁安。
We are a T-plus 223 days, 6 hours, 32 minutes.
我们是T + 223天，6小时32分钟。
All systems are go. All lights are green.
所有的系统都去了。所有灯都是绿色的。
We are awaiting the start of the final television transmissions
我们正在等待
from the Command Module on its return to Earth.
命令模块返回地球后最终电视传输的开始。
This is specifically a conversation between the crew and their wives.
这特别是船员和他们的妻子之间的对话。
This is the first time the crew has been close enough to Earth
这是船员第一次与地球足够接近
to make normal conversation feasible.
，使正常的谈话成为可能。
This is Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯座控制。
Capricorn One, this is Houston. Capricorn One, this is Houston.
摩羯座一号，这是休斯顿。摩羯座一号，这是休斯顿。
Roger, Houston, this is Capricorn One.
罗杰，休斯顿，这是摩羯座一号。
Houston, do you have a picture?
休斯顿，你有照片吗？
Roger, Capricorn, we have a picture.
罗杰，摩羯座，我们有一张照片。
We have three anxious ladies here who would like to talk to you.
我们这里有三个焦虑的女士，她们想跟你说话。
Roger, Houston.
罗杰，休斯顿。
We'd sure like to talk to them.
我们肯定想和他们谈谈。
Okay, go ahead, but keep it short.
好的，继续吧，但要保持简短。
Remember, this is long distance.
记住，这是长距离的。
Jack?
插口？
Jack, it's Betty.
杰克，这是贝蒂。
Hey, Betty, how are you? You look fine.
嘿，贝蒂，你好吗？你看起来不错。
Thanks. You know we can't see you up here, but you sure sound terrific.
谢谢。你知道我们在这里看不到你，但你确实听起来很棒。
I miss you. So do the kids.
我想你。孩子们也一样。
Okay, I miss them too, more than you all know.
好吧，我也想念他们，比你们都知道的更多。
Peter?
彼得？
It's Sharon.
这是沙龙。
I told you never to call me here.
我告诉过你永远不要在这里给我打电话。
Are you feeling well?
你感觉怎么样？
I'm feeling very well.
我感觉很好。
How's Sandy?
桑迪怎么样？
Well, she's got the part of Wendy in her school play.
好吧，她在学校的比赛中得到了温迪的一部分。
They're doing Peter Pan.
他们正在做彼得潘。
That's terrific.
真了不起。
You sound so close.
你的声音如此接近。
It's hard to believe you really are that far away in space.
很难相信你真的离太空太远了。
It's hard for me to believe it, too.
我也很难相信它。
Bru?
ぷ？
Hello, Kay.
你好，凯。
We're all so proud of you.
我们都为你感到骄傲。
Can you hear me, Bru?
布鲁恩，你能听见我吗？
Yes.
是。
I'm not sure of Brubaker. Keep watching.
我不确定布鲁贝克。一直在看。
Bru? I have a surprise for you.
ぷ？我有个惊喜给你。
What?
什么？
I said I have a surprise for you.
我说我有一个惊喜。
What is it?
它是什么？
Charles wrote a composition in school and he won an award.
查尔斯在学校写了一篇作文，并获得了一个奖项。
May I read it to you?
我可以给你看看吗？
Bru, can you hear me?
布鲁，你能听见我吗？
Yes...
是的...?
please, read it to me.
拜托，请读给我听。
It doesn't look good. Do I cut the transmission?
它看起来不太好。我切断传输吗？
Not until I tell you.
直到我告诉你。
'My father, by Charles Brubaker, Jr.'
“我的父亲，小查尔斯布鲁贝克，小姐。”?
'My father is far away from me now.
“我父亲现在远离我。
He is flying to Mars.
他飞往火星。
I miss him very much.
我非常想念他。
I always miss him when he goes away.
他离开时我总是想念他。
I'm not sad, though.
不过，我并不难过。
I used to be sad when he went away.
他离开时我曾经很伤心。
One day he told me that people can't live only for themselves.
有一天他告诉我，人们不能只为自己而活。
He said he was trying to do something that would be good for everybody.
他说他正在尝试做一些对每个人都有益的事情。
I know that is what he is doing now.
我知道他现在正在做的事情。
He is doing something for everybody, to give them a better life.
他正在为每个人做点什么，让他们过上更好的生活。
That means he is doing something for me, too.
这意味着他也在为我做点什么。
So even though he is far away,
因此即使他很远，
he is thinking about me and I am with him.
他也在考虑我，我和他在一起。
That is why I'm not sad.
这就是为什么我不难过。
That is why I'm so proud of my Dad.
这就是为什么我为我的爸爸感到骄傲。
I love him so much.'
我很爱他。'?
Kay.
凯。
What is it?
它是什么？
There's something I...
有一些我......?
I wanna say.
我想说的。
Bru?
ぷ？
What is it?
它是什么？
Not until I tell you.
直到我告诉你。
I know this hasn't been easy for you and the kids.
我知道这对你和孩子来说并不容易。
I want you to know
我想让你知道
I love you.
我爱你。
Tell Charles thanks for the composition, please.
请告诉Charles谢谢你的作文。
I will.
我会。
Tell him when I get back,
当我回来时告诉他，
I'm gonna take him to Yosemite again,
我会
like last summer.
像去年夏天一样带他去Yosemite?。
I will.
我会。
And I want you to know that I love you.
我希望你知道我爱你。
Very much.
非常。
Time's up, gentlemen.
时间到了，先生们。
Roger, Houston.
罗杰，休斯顿。
The next time we see you, you'll be on the way home.
下次我们见到你，你就会回家的路上。
Roger. Well done, Capricorn.
罗杰。干得好，摩羯座。
Yes?
是？
Is Whitter in? Tell him it's Caulfield.
是谁？告诉他这是Caulfield。
Who? Whitter. Elliot Whitter.
谁？Whitter。艾略特惠特。
There's no one here by that name.
这个名字在这里没有人。
You must have the wrong apartment.
你必须有错的公寓。
Well, this is apartment 228, isn't it?
嗯，这是公寓228，不是吗？
Yeah. Oh, you probably have the wrong building.
是啊。哦，你可能错了。
You know, they are all sorta look alike.
你知道，他们看起来都很相似。
Yeah, that's right. This is 4311 Claridge, isn't it?
是啊，没错。这是4311 Claridge，不是吗？
Yeah, it is.
是啊，就是。
Elliot Whitter lives at 4311 Claridge, in apartment 228.
Elliot Whitter住在4311 Claridge，在228号公寓。
Is this a joke?
这是个笑话吗？
Look, I've been here a million times.
看，我来过这里一百万次。
Elliot's a friend of mine and he lives in this apartment!
艾略特是我的一个朋友，他住在这间公寓里！
Look, Mister..., whoever you are. I'm cleaning an oven.
看，先生......，无论你是谁。我正在打扫烤箱。
It's my oven. It's in my kitchen. In my apartment.
这是我的烤箱。它在我的厨房里。在我的公寓里。
If you don't mind, I'd like to get back to it.
如果你不介意，我想回到它。
Wait a minute! Just wait! Look, I'm not a crazy person and I'm not a mugger!
等一下！等一下！看，我不是一个疯子，我不是一个抢劫者！
I'm looking for my friend and he lives in this apartment! I swear it!
我正在寻找我的朋友，他住在这间公寓里！我发誓！
Would you get your foot out of my door or I'm gonna call the police!
你会把脚伸出我的门，还是打电话给警察！
Now I don't think this is funny any more!
现在我觉得这不再有趣了！
Wait. I can prove I've been here before. I know this apartment.
等待。我可以证明我以前来过这里。我知道这间公寓。
Now, will you get outta here, or do I have to call the police?
现在，你会离开这里，还是我必须报警？
This is Paul Cunningham, Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯控制的保罗坎宁安。
We are 259 days 14 hours, 12 minutes, into the flight.
我们是259天14小时12分钟，在飞行中。
All systems are normal. All lights are green.
所有系统都正常。所有灯都是绿色的。
The prime recovery ship, the U.S.S. Oriskany, is in position.
主要的恢复船，Oriskany号航空母舰就位。
An on-target landing should result in recovery time
目标着陆应该导致
of 18 minutes. from splash-down to the opening of the hatch.
18分钟的恢复时间。从飞溅到舱口的开口。
After the crew delivers its speech on the Oriskany deck
在船员在Oriskany甲板上发表讲话
and is welcomed aboard by Captain Earl Marks,
并受到Earl Marks上尉的欢迎之后，
they'll be taken below deck for a medical debriefing.
他们将被带到甲板下面进行医疗情况汇报。
Tonight, at 8 o'clock Pacific Daylight Time,
今晚8点太平洋夏令时，
the crew will attend the victory banquet topped by a special dessert,
船员将参加胜利宴会，上面有一个特殊的甜点，
a 40 feet red cake, depicting the Martian surface.
一个40英尺的红色蛋糕，描绘了火星表面。
We are 23 minutes. 12 seconds. from the beginning of the re-entry phase.
我们是23分钟。12秒?从重新进入阶段开始。
This is Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯座控制。
We have a chopper waiting on the island
我们有一个直升飞机在岛上等
to take you to the spacecraft when it splashes down.
你飞溅时带你去飞船。
It'll take the Oriskany about 1.30 hour to reach you, so there won't be any rush.
它将花费大约1.30小时的Oriskany到达你，所以不会有任何匆忙。
All lights are green.
所有灯都是绿色的。
Roger. All green.
罗杰。全绿。
Separation thruster check list? The propulsion?
分离推进器检查清单？推进？
Separation thruster check list.
分离推进器检查表。
Outboard thrusters.
舷外推进器。
Outboard thrusters on.
Inboard thrusters.
内侧推进器。
Inboard thrusters on. How we doin'?
内侧推进器。我们怎么办？
We might have a slight problem, sir.
先生，我们可能会遇到一些问题。
What is it? They're a little bit off target.
它是什么？他们有点偏离目标。
How far off?
离我有多远？
As much as 200 miles. That far?
多达200英里。那么远？
It could take up to 1.30 hour for the recovery forces to reach them.
恢复部队可能需要1.30小时才能到达他们。
Keep me posted. Yes, sir.
让我发布。是的先生。
Six...
六......?
five...
五......?
four... three...
四......三......?
two...
二......?
Capricorn One, this is Houston.
摩羯座一，这是休斯顿。
Capricorn One, we show red on the heat shield.
摩羯座一号，我们在隔热罩上显示红色。
Do you copy?
你复制了吗？
Capricorn One, this is Houston.
摩羯座一号，这是休斯顿。
We show red on the heat shield. Do you read?
我们在隔热罩上显示红色。你读过吗？
Capricorn One, this is Houston.
摩羯座一号，这是休斯顿。
Capricorn One, this is Houston. We show red on the heat shield.
摩羯座一号，这是休斯顿。我们在隔热罩上显示红色。
Do you copy?
你复制了吗？
Capricorn One, this is Houston.
摩羯座一号，这是休斯顿。
Capricorn One, we show red on the heat shield. Do you copy?
摩羯座一号，我们在隔热罩上显示红色。你复制了吗？
Capricorn One... That is, Kelloway.
摩羯座一......就是，Kelloway。
Capricorn One, this is Houston. Do you read?
摩羯座一号，这是休斯顿。你读过吗？
Capricorn One, this is Houston.
摩羯座一号，这是休斯顿。
Capricorn One, we show red on the heat shield. Do you copy?
摩羯座一号，我们在隔热罩上显示红色。你复制了吗？
Capricorn One, this is Houston. Capricorn One, this is Houston.
摩羯座一号，这是休斯顿。摩羯座一号，这是休斯顿。
Capricorn One, this is Houston.
摩羯座一号，这是休斯顿。
Capricorn, we show red light on the heat shield. Do you copy?
摩羯座，我们在隔热罩上显示红灯。你复制了吗？
Capricorn One, this is Houston.
摩羯座一号，这是休斯顿。
This is Paul Cunningham, Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯控制的保罗坎宁安。
We are advised that there appears to be a malfunction.
我们被告知似乎有故障。
We do not know what the problem is. We will keep you advised.
我们不知道问题是什么。我们会为您提供建议。
This is Capricorn Control.
这是摩羯座控制。
Charles, take Sandy and go inside.
查尔斯，带桑迪进去。
Mom, what's... Charles, go inside now!
妈妈，什么......查尔斯，现在进去！
Mom... Charles, I said right now!
妈妈......查尔斯，我现在说！
Capricorn One, this is Houston.
摩羯座一号，这是休斯顿。
Ladies and gentlemen, I have a brief statement
女士们，先生们，我有一个简短的发言
and then I will answer your questions.
，然后我会回答你们的问题。
It must have been re-entry.
它一定是重新进入。
Something went wrong during re-entry.
重新入境时出了点问题。
Why haven't they told us anything?
他们为什么不告诉我们什么？
They don't want us to know what went wrong.
他们不希望我们知道出了什么问题。
What went wrong?
什么地方出了错？
Who the hell is Kelloway? Where the hell are we?
Kelloway到底是谁？我们到底在哪里？
At T-plus 259 days 15 hours, 11 minutes, in the flight of Capricorn One,
在摩羯座一号飞行的T-plus 259天15小时11分钟，
which is 2 minutes. 18 seconds. after interface,
这是2分钟。18秒?在界面之后，
the heat shield light on the Mission Control monitoring panel turned red.
任务控制监视面板上的隔热罩指示灯变为红色。
We...
我们......?
are dead.
已经死了。
What? We're dead.
什么？我们死了?
Shit, I was such a terrific guy!
妈的，我真是个好人！
We tried to establish radio contract, contact with the spacecraft
我们试图建立无线电合同，与航天器接触
an we were unsuccessful.
我们没有成功。
It landed off course. Why haven't they said anything to us?
它落地了。为什么他们没有对我们说什么？
And if it never landed, either the heat shield separated
如果它从未落地，要么隔热罩分开，要么
or the chutes never opened.
滑道从未打开过。
Either way, we are dead.
无论哪种方式，我们都死了。
The heat shield evidently separated from the Command Module
热屏蔽显然与命令模块分离
and, as you know, the heat shield
，如您所知，热屏蔽
is the only protection the Module has
是模块
against the heat build-up on the re-entering the Earth's atmosphere.
对重新进入地球大气层时产生的热量的唯一保护。
The spacecraft disintegrated within 12 seconds. after the loss of the heat shield.
宇宙飞船在12秒内解体。失去隔热罩后。
Right now Kelloway is making a speech
现在，Kelloway正在发表
about what brave, wonderful guys...
关于勇敢，优秀的人......?
we were.
我们的演讲。
I cannot adequately describe how we feel.
我无法充分描述我们的感受。
These men were an integral of the family...
这些人是家庭中不可或缺的一部分......?
here in the program.
在这个项目中。
If anybody ever sees us again, the whole thing falls apart.
如果有人再次看到我们，整个事情就会崩溃。
It's as simple as that. They can't have us around.
就这么简单。他们不能让我们身边。
That is the end of my statement.
那是我发言的结尾。
Have you spoken to the families? Yes.
你和家人说过话吗？是。
I don't know how we have a lotta choice in this matter.
我不知道我们在这件事上有多少选择。
I say we get the hell outta here. Anybody disagree?
我说我们在这里得到了地狱。有人不同意吗？
When was the last time the heat shield was checked?
最后一次检查隔热罩是什么时候？
All during the re-entry phase there were a series of status checks.
所有在重新进入阶段都进行了一系列状态检查。
All of them gave us every indication the shield was in place.
所有这些都给了我们盾牌到位的一切迹象。
No, I have not spoken to the President yet, but I'm sure I will very soon.
不，我还没有和总统谈过，但我相信我会很快。
I'd like to say that the President has been
我想说，总统一直是
a constant source of encouragement to all of us in the program.
我们所有人在该计划中的鼓励源泉。
This mission meant as much to him as it did to us.
这个任务对他来说意味着和对我们一样多。
Do you think this will end the Manned Space Program?
你认为这会结束载人航天计划吗？
I don't know.
我不知道。
You can't reach that far without stumbling somewhere along the way.
如果没有在路上的某个地方绊倒，你就无法到达那么远。
That doesn't mean that your goal isn't worthwhile.
这并不意味着你的目标不值得。
So many people have given so much.
很多人都给了这么多。
In 1967 we had the Apollo One fire.
1967年，我们得到了阿波罗一号火。
But we didn't just...
但
give up even though we were crushed.
即使我们被压垮，我们也不只是......?放弃。
We went on as they would have wanted us to.
我们继续按原样要求我们这样做。
Now, these three remarkable men
现在，这三位杰出的人
have given their lives in an effort to...
为了
widen the horizons of their species.
扩大他们物种的视野而牺牲了自己的生命。
They died striving for a goal.
他们为争取目标而牺牲。
You tell me.
你告诉我。
I ask you... I ask all of you here. You be the ones to tell me.
我问你......我在这里问你们所有人。你是那些告诉我的人。
How could we best serve these men?
我们怎样才能最好地为这些人服务？
By giving up on their dream?
放弃他们的梦想？
By saying that
说
it was all for nothing?
这一切都是无用的？
You give me the answer.
你给我答案。
That was the left gear we lost. See if you can retract the other one.
那是我们丢失的左档。看看你是否可以收回另一个。
Do you have any idea where we are? No.
你知道我们在哪里吗？不
Which direction are we headed?
，我们朝哪个方向前进？
West. Once we hit the coast, we'll go North.
西方。一旦我们到达海岸，我们就会去北方。
All we've got to do is get to any city, any place there are people,
我们所要做的就是到达任何城市，任何地方都有人，
a newspaper, a television station.
报纸，电视台。
Any place we can show up and be seen. Then it's over.
我们可以出现并被看到的任何地方。然后就结束了。
I'm not sure it's exactly over.
我不确定它到底是什么时候。
Our families, our kids. They think we're dead.
我们的家人，我们的孩子。他们认为我们已经死了。
I wonder,
我想知道，
when we show up, when everybody finds up,
当我们出现时，每个人都找到了，
I wonder if they'll be happy.
我想知道他们是否会幸福。
Maybe it'd be better for them if we were dead.
如果我们死了，也许对他们来说会更好。
Oh, Christ!
哦，基督！
Fuel! There's no Goddamn fuel!
汽油！没有该死的燃料！
I told you never to take a trip without checking the tank.
What about the reserve? We're on reserve.
保护区怎么样？我们保留了。
That's great.
那很棒。
I'll start to circle. See if you can find a lever area.
我会开始圈。看看你是否能找到一个杠杆区域。
There.
那里。
Over there, beyond those cliffs.
在那边，超越那些悬崖。
Are you sure you know how to land this thing?
你确定你知道如何着陆这件事吗？
Full flaps.
全襟翼。
I think we're on Mars.
我想我们在火星上。
We got about 20 minutes. head start on them.
我们大约20分钟。从头开始吧。
It's not gonna be hard to spot this plane from the air.
从空中发现这架飞机并不难。
We got two choices,
我们有两个选择，
either we stick together, or we split up and go in different directions.
要么我们团结在一起，要么我们分开并走向不同的方向。
Hey, I just found a survival kit in here.
嘿，我刚刚在这里找到了救生包。
There's a can of water each.
每个都有一罐水。
A flare each.
各个耀斑。
John, you take the flint. Peter and I'll split up the matches.
约翰，你拿燧石。彼得和我将分开比赛。
Anybody want the gun?
有人想要枪吗？
I'd shoot my foot.
我会射脚。
I'd shoot his foot.
我会射他的脚。
You can take the knife.
你可以拿刀。
Remember, if any of us gets caught,
请记住，如果我们中的任何一个人被抓住，
or he can't make it, shoot off a flare,
或者他无法抓住它，就会射出一个闪光，
so the others'll know.
所以其他人都会知道。
I'll continue West. John, you go North. Peter, you go South.
我会继续西部。约翰，你去北方。彼得，你去南方。
We came from the East,
我们来自东方，
so we know that's the wrong way.
所以我们知道这是错误的方式。
There's not a lotta time.
没有多少时间。
There's too much to say, so let's go.
有太多话要说了，让我们走吧。
If any of us makes it...
如果我们中的任何一个人做到了......?
Well...
嗯......?
Did I ever tell you the one about the guy who had a job giving enemas
我有没有告诉过你那个曾经给
to elephants, and?
大象灌肠的人呢？
Thanks.
谢谢。
Did you ever hear it?
你听过吗？
You can tell me about it when we get home.
我们回家后你可以告诉我。
Tell Charles that...
告诉查尔斯......请
thank him for the composition, please.
感谢他的作文。
I...
一世...
Well, tell him when I get back...
好吧，当我回来的时候告诉他......?
I'm gonna take him to Yosemite again,
我会
like last summer.
像去年夏天一样把他带到优胜美地。
I will. Right there. Run it again.
我会。在那里。再次运行它。
Like last summer.
像去年夏天一样。
I will.
我会。
'Look, sir. Look, sir.
“看，先生。看，先生。
Mr. Knox, sir, let's do tricks with bricks and blocks, sir.
诺克斯先生，先生，先生，让我们用积木做块。
Let's do tricks with chicks and clocks, sir.'
先生，让我们用小鸡和时钟做招数吧。
Blocks! Look, blocks! Right.
块！看，块！对。
There are the blocks and those are the...
有块，那些是...?
Clocks! Right.
时钟！对。
'First, I'll make a quick trick, brick stack.
'首先，我会做一个快速的技巧，砖堆。
Then I'll make a quick trick, block stack.
然后我会做一个快速的技巧，阻止堆栈。
You can make a quick trick, chick stack.
你可以快速制作小鸡叠。
You can make a quick trick, clock stack.
你可以快速制作技巧，时钟堆栈。
Chicks! And?
小鸡！和？
Clocks!
钟！
'And here's a new trick, Mr. Knox.
“这是一个新技巧，诺克斯先生。
Socks on chicks and chicks on fox.
在小鸡和小鸡的袜子在狐狸。
Fox on clocks, on bricks and blocks.
狐狸在时钟上，砖和块上。
Bricks and blocks on fox and box.
在狐狸和箱子的砖和块。?先生，
Now we come to
我们来到
ticks and tocks, sir.
蜱虫和袜子。
Try to say this,
试着这么说吧，
Mr. Knox, sir,
诺克斯先生，先生，
clocks...
钟表......?
clocks on fix tick,
钟表上的
clocks on Knox tock.
钟表，诺克斯托克的钟表。
Clocks!
钟！
Clocks.
时钟。
Right, Sandy, very good.
对，桑迪，非常好。
'Six, sick,
“六，病，
bricks,
砖，
tick...'
嘀......”?
Yes?
是的？
I'd like to see Mrs. Brubaker. My name is Caulfield.
我想见布鲁巴克太太。我叫考菲尔德。
Mrs. Brubaker isn't seeing anyone.
布鲁巴克太太没有见到任何人。
I telephoned this morning. I believe I'm expected.
我今天早上打来电话。我相信我的期望。
What was that name again? Caulfield. Robert Caulfield.
那又是什么名字？考菲尔德。罗伯特考菲尔德。
Oh, yes. Mrs. Brubaker is expecting you.
哦，是的。布鲁巴克太太很期待你。
She's out on the patio. It's right through there.
她在露台上。它就在那里。
Thank you
谢谢
Mrs. Brubaker? Mr. Caulfield?
Brubaker夫人？考尔菲尔德先生？
Sit down, please.
请坐下。
Mrs. Brubaker, first of all,
布鲁巴克太太，首先，
I'd like to say I'm really sorry.
我想说我很抱歉。
Everyone is sor... I know, and I appreciate it.
每个人都是我的...我知道，我很感激。
Don't be too uncomfortable with me. I couldn't put up with that right now.
不要对我太不舒服。我现在无法忍受。
I understand that you think you're interrupting me,
我知道你认为你打扰了我，
and you are, but I welcome the interruption.
而你是，但我欢迎中断。
You called and said it was something important. What is it?
你打来电话说它很重要。它是什么？
Mrs. Brubaker, it may not be important to you.
布鲁巴克太太，对你来说可能并不重要。
I'm looking for something that may be important to me. It's personal.
我正在寻找对我来说很重要的事情。这是私事。
You're a reporter, aren't you?
你是记者，不是吗？
Yes, as I told you, I'm not looking for an interview.
是的，就像我告诉你的那样，我
I would like to ask you a few questions
我想问你几次
about the last time you spoke with your husband after the landing.
关于你最后一次与你丈夫谈话后的问题。
What about it?
怎么样？
Well, this may sound strange, Mrs. Brubaker, don't be upset with me.
嗯，这可能听起来很奇怪，布鲁贝克太太，不要对我不高兴。
Just before the conversation ended,
在谈话结束前，
Colonel Brubaker told you something about going on a vacation
布鲁贝克上校告诉你一些关于去度假的事情
and your reaction was like you didn't understand what he was saying.
，你的反应就像你不明白他在说什么。
Why would you wanna know about that?
你为什么想知道这个？
As I told you, it's something personal.
正如我告诉过你的，这是个人的。
It's personal to me, too.
对我来说也是个人的。
Please, I'm not trying to embarrass you or anyone else.
拜托，我不是想让你或其他任何人难堪。
Why would any of this be your business?
为什么这会是你的业务？
Please, trust me.
请相信我。
Why?
为什么？
You ask really good questions.
你问的确很好。
Well, it's all so silly.
好吧，这一切都太傻了。
It wasn't anything that dramatic.
这不是戏剧性的东西。
Bru just forgot something, that's all.
布鲁只是忘了什么，就是这样。
I don't see the purpose in broadcasting that my husband mistook a vacation
我没有看到广播的目的，
when he had so many other things to think about.
当他有太多其他事情要考虑时，我的丈夫误以为假。
No, no, no, I'm not looking for anything to broadcast.
不，不，不，我不是要找广播的东西。
What are you looking for? It has to do with a friend of mine.
你在找什么？这与我的一个朋友有关。
Is there something I should know? lf there was anything, I would tell you.
有什么我应该知道的吗？如果有什么，我会告诉你。
Well, it's nothing.
嗯，没什么。
Bru said that he wanted to go back to Yosemite like last year.
布鲁说，他想像去年一样回到优胜美地。
Last year, we went to Flat Rock, not Yosemite.
去年，我们去了Flat Rock，而不是优胜美地。
I don't think there's any cosmic significance in that.
我不认为这有任何宇宙意义。
Mrs. Brubaker, I truly thank you.
布鲁巴克太太，我真的很感谢你。
I'm sure you had better things to do
我相信你有更好的事情要做
than put up with a bunch of stupid questions.
而不是忍受一堆愚蠢的问题。
No, I didn't. Have I been any help to you at all?
不，我没有。我对你有任何帮助吗？
I don't know. May I call you again, sometime?
我不知道。有时候我可以再打电话给你吗？
Yes.
是。
Yes?
是？
There's no one inside?
里面没有人？
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
Get more personnel, they can't go too far on foot.
获得更多人员，他们不能走得太远。
Oh, a piece of cake.
哦，小菜一碟。
Charles, cut it out. You know you're bothering her.
查尔斯，把它剪掉了。你知道你在困扰她。
I know you're bothering her and she knows you're bothering her.
我知道你在困扰她，她知道你在困扰她。
If you want to stay in the pool, cut it out.
如果你想留在游泳池，切掉它。
Hi, Uncle Jim. Hello there, Charles.
嗨，吉姆叔叔。你好，查尔斯。
Hello, Kay. Jim.
你好，凯。吉姆。
You look just fine.
你看起来很好。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Can I offer you something to drink?
我能为你提供一些饮料吗？
No, thank you.
不，谢谢。
How are the children? Fine.
孩子们怎么样？精细。
Charles is strong.
查尔斯很强大。
He's very much to himself, but he's strong.
他非常喜欢自己，但他很坚强。
Sandy doesn't know.
桑迪不知道。
There's gonna be a Memorial Service on Tuesday, right here, in Houston.
周二将在休斯顿举行纪念仪式。
President... The President'll be here.
总统......总统会在这里。
He's going to speak. That's nice.
他会发言。真好。
Will I get a folded flag?
我会得到折叠旗帜吗？
I would like you to be there.
我希望你能在那里。
Please.
请。
I know how difficult everything is for you right now.
我知道现在一切对你来说有多难。
I feel like Jack the Ripper even asking you... It's just that...
我觉得开膛手杰克甚至会问你......就是这样......?
it would be good for everyone if you could go with me to the service.
如果你能跟我一起去服务那对每个人都有好处。
It's a horrible way to die. No, absolutely not.
这是一种可怕的死亡方式。不，绝对不是。
When the heat shield separated, it was over in less than 5 seconds.
当隔热罩分开时，它在不到5秒钟内结束。
I know that sounds grizzly, but you just have to know he never suffered.
我知道这听起来很灰白，但你只需要知道他从未遭受过。
He died doing what he wanted to do.
他做了他想做的事情。
Something he felt was important enough to die for.
他觉得有些东西很重要，可以为之而死。
I know, I know.
我知道我知道。
I don't think it was important enough for him to die for.
我不认为让他死的重要。
I understand.
我明白。
I'm sorry, I'm so sorry.
对不起，我很抱歉。
I have no right to intrude on you like this. I'll call you tomorrow.
我无权像这样侵入你。我明天给你打电话。
Jim!
吉姆！
I'll go.
我会去。
You're a very special woman.
你是一个非常特别的女人。
He was a very special man.
他是一个非常特别的人。
Thank you.
谢谢。
Hey, Uncle Jim! Yes?
嘿，吉姆叔叔！是？
My Dad went to Mars. Yes! Yes, he did!
我的爸爸去了火星。是!?是他做的！
Oh, I'm dehydrating.
哦，我正在脱水。
Dehydrating.
脱水。
Sign.
标志。
Manual says...
手册说......?
look for signs.
寻找迹象。
Water.
水。
Manual says...
手册说......?
signs for water.
水的迹象。
Oh, dried river bed.
哦，干河床。
Signs.
迹象。
Bend in the river.
弯曲在河里。
Lower signs.
较低的迹象。
Bend in the river.
弯曲在河里。
There's just...
只有...?
Water.
水。
River bed.
河床。
Water.
水。
A drink of water.
喝一杯水。
Elizabeth, there's no water.
伊丽莎白，没有水。
There's no water.
没有水。
I wanna die.
我想死。
Elizabeth.
伊丽莎白。
Birds.
鸟类。
Elizabeth,
伊丽莎白，
birds.
鸟类。
I got to get the birds.
我得到了鸟儿。
Helicopters...
直升机......?
Yes?
是吗？
He was alone?
他独自一人？
Which direction was he heading from the airplane?
他从飞机前往哪个方向？
Aah, look South and West only.
啊，只看南方和西方。
Call everybody off North and East.
打电话给北方和东方的所有人。
The other two are South and West.
另外两个是南方和西方。
Hello, again. Hello, again.
再次问好。再次问好。
Can I offer you something to drink? Yes, thank you.
我能为你提供一些饮料吗？是的，谢谢。
What would you like? Some scotch. Straight, please.
你喜欢什么？一些苏格兰威士忌。请直接?
You haven't found what you're looking for,
你还没有找到你想要的东西，
you're embarrassed about bothering me again,
你又为再次困扰我而感到尴尬，
however there were one or two questions more you'd like to ask me.
但是你想问我一两个问题。
It's something personal and you won't bother me any more.
这是个人的事情，你不会再打扰我了。
I haven't found what I'm looking for. I feel embarrassed about bothering you.
我还没找到我想要的东西。我为打扰你而感到尴尬。
However, there are one or two more questions I'd like to ask you.
但是，我想问你一两个问题。
It's something personal and I won't bother you any more.
这是个人的事情，我不会再打扰你了。
You're up to something, want my help and you won't tell me what it is. Why?
你需要我的帮助，你不会告诉我它是什么。为什么？
You're a very smart lady, you know that.
你知道，你是一个非常聪明的女士。
Yes.
I drink too much.
我喝得太多了。
I get in trouble a lot because I talk too much.
我经常遇到麻烦，因为我谈得太多了。
Sometimes I have an imagination that's a bit too vivid.
有时我的想象力有点过于生动。
Something's wrong and I don't know what it is.
出了点问题，我不知道它是什么。
Believe me, I would never do anything to harm you or your husband, I swear.
相信我，我发誓永远不会伤害你或你的丈夫。
What are you after?
你在追求什么？
I'm taking a terrible risk telling you this.
我冒着很大的风险告诉你这件事。
You may throw me out of here and I do not want to be thrown out.
你可能会把我赶出这里，我不想被抛弃。
I don't think your husband is the kind of man who makes mistakes,
我不认为你的丈夫是那种犯错误的人，
no matter how far away he may be.
无论他有多远。
I think he was trying to tell you something.
我想他想告诉你一件事。
What? What did you do at Flat Rock?
什么？你在Flat Rock做了什么？
Nothing much.
没什么。
We came home after one day because Charles got sick.
有一天我们回家了，因为查尔病了。
What'd you do that one day? I don't remember.
你有一天做了什么？我不记得了。
We took a tour of the town. They have those tours.
我们参观了这个小镇。他们有这些旅游。
And...
而且......?
I don't remember what.
我不记得是什么了。
We took some home movies. Do you have them?
我们拍了一些家庭电影。你有吗？
Yes. May I see them?
是。我可以看看他们吗？
Yes.
是。
They were making a movie the day we were there.
我们在那里的那天，他们正在拍电影。
Bru got a big kick out of it.
布鲁恩得到了很大的帮助。
He never knew it took so much time to just do one simple scene.
他从来不知道花一么多时间做一个简单的场景。
Charles loves that one. He wasn't in the greatest mood.
查尔斯喜欢那个。他心情不好。
He didn't know it but he was sick.
他不知道，但他生病了。
Bru was fascinated with the detail.
布鲁恩对细节很着迷。
He couldn't get over how something so fake could look so real.
他无法克服这些假装看起来如此真实的东西。
He kept on saying that with that kind of technology
他一直说，通过这种技术，
you could convince people of almost anything.
你几乎可以说服人们。
There's this guy, you see!
你看，有这个人！
He takes a trip to Europe.
他去欧洲旅行。
It's his first vacation
这是他
in a long time.
很长一段时间的第一次假期。
He sees the sights, you know?
他知道，他看到了景点吗？
He has a real good time.
他真的很开心。
Anyway,
无论如何，
after a while he decides to call home.
过了一会儿他决定打电话回家。
He get his brother on the phone and the guy says to his brother,
他让他的兄弟打电话，那家伙对他的兄弟说：
'How's everything at home?'
“家里的一切都好吗？”?
And his brother says,
他的兄弟说，
'Your... Your cat died.'
'你的......你的猫死了。'?
And the guy says to his brother,
那家伙对他的兄弟说，
'You shouldn't tell me bad news like that.'
“你不应该告诉我这样的坏消息。”?
'You should
“你应该
break it to me gently.
轻轻地打破它。
You know...
你知道......?
You should say something like,
你应该说一句话，
'The cat crawled out on the roof
'猫爬在屋顶上
and the was chasing the squirrels
，正在追逐松鼠
and...
......
he got stuck.
他卡住了?
We had to call the fire department
我们不得不打电话给消防部门
and when they finally got there, a fireman crawled up,
，当他们最终到达那里时，一名消防员爬上来，
he grabbed the cat
他抓住那只猫
and on the way down he slipped and the cat fell to the ground.'
，在下来的路上他滑倒了，猫掉到了地上。
'They had to take the cat to the vet.
他们不得不把猫带到兽医那里。
They tried to save the cat.
他们试图救猫。
They even operated
他们甚至
on the cat.
对猫进行操作。
But it was too late.
但为时已晚了。
They couldn't
他们无法
save the cat.'
拯救这只猫。
That's how you should break
这就是你应该如何打破坏
bad news, like that.'
消息。
So the guy says to his brother,
那家伙对他哥哥说：
'How's Mom?'
'妈妈怎么样？'?
And the brother says,
兄弟说，
'She's on the roof.
'她在屋顶上。
Get it?
得到它？
She's on the roof.
她在屋顶上。
Get it?'
得到它？'?
Yes?
是？
Which one?
哪一个？
What direction was he going?
他走向什么方向？
Brubaker is going West. Put everybody West.
布鲁贝克正在往西走。把每个人都放在西方。
Caulfield.
考菲尔德。
Right now?
马上？
Okay.
好的。
How nice of you to join us here!
你真高兴加入我们吧！
Listen, I think I got something. You need a dermatologist?
听着，我想我有所收获。你需要皮肤科医生吗？
Don't tell me, I'll get it.
不要告诉我，我会明白的。
George Raft! Right? Where the hell have you been?
乔治筏！对？你到底去了哪里？
I have to talk to you.
我得和你谈谈。
I think I'm onto something. It could be your actual ball game. I mean it.
我想我正在做点什么。这可能是你真正的球赛。我是认真的。
Golly, gee, Scoop, that sounds very interesting!
Golly，gee，Scoop，听起来很有趣！
Something is wrong. Something big.
出了点问题。有点大。
They know I'm onto it and they tried to kill me.
他们知道我在上面，他们试图杀了我。
Who's they? I can't tell you.
他们是谁？我不能告诉你。
Why not? You wouldn't believe me.
为什么不？你不会相信我。
You don't think so?
你不这么认为吗？
Okay, listen to me. I got a tip from a friend,
好的，听我说?我得到了一位朋友，
a good friend, then he disappeared.
一位好朋友的小费，然后他消失了。
Disappeared?
消失了？
Like he never existed. There's some lady living in his apartment.
就像他从未存在过一样。有一位女士住在他的公寓里。
His apartment is all different.
他的公寓各不相同。
She said she's been living there for more than a year.
她说她已经在那里生活了一年多。
I checked the building rental office.
我检查了大楼租赁办公室。
They have receipts from her for more than a year.
他们收到了一年多的收据。
I checked NAS A personnel.
我检查了NAS A人员。
They have no record my friend ever worked there.
他们没有记录我的朋友在那里工作过。
They say they never even heard of him.
他们说他们从未听说过他。
So this friend of yours,
所以你的朋友，你
who works at NAS A, gives you a tip, then disappears.
在NAS A工作，给你一个提示，然后消失。
And it turns out that he never lived in his apartment or worked at NAS A.
事实证明，他从未住在他的公寓里或在NAS A工作过。
This is the guy that gave you the tip on your cosmic scoop,
这就是那个给你提示宇宙勺子的人，
and you think I won't believe you? My car!
而你认为我不相信你？我的车！
Someone tampered with my car!
有人篡改了我的车！
The one you decided to go swimming with?
你决定去游泳的那个？
They did something to it! I couldn't stop it!
他们做了些什么！我无法阻止它！
Can you prove that?
你能证明吗？
The police said...
警方说......?
They said that nothing was wrong. And you think I won't believe you.
他们说没有错。而且你认为我不会相信你。
Somebody took a shot at me!
有人对我开枪！
When? Yesterday.
什么时候？昨天。
Thank God, I've got an alibi! I'm telling you the truth!
感谢上帝，我有一个不在犯罪现场！我告诉你实话！
Listen to me and listen good.
听我说，听好。
I don't like you, Caulfield. You're ambitious.
考菲尔德，我不喜欢你。你雄心勃勃。
You think the way to get ahead is to come up with the scoop of the century.
你认为获得成功的方法是提出本世纪的独家新闻。
Woodward and Bernstein were good reporters. That's how they did it.
伍德沃德和伯恩斯坦都是好记者。他们就是这样做的。
Not by telling me they've located Patty Hearst three times, like you did.
不是告诉我他们已经找到帕蒂赫斯特三次，
Or that brilliant piece of investigative journalism you pulled off,
或者
by finding an eyewitness to the 2nd gunman in the Kennedy assassination.
通过在肯尼迪遇刺事件中找到第二名枪手的目击者，你发现了这部精彩的调查性新闻。
The small fact that the man had been in a mental institution at the time,
那个男人当时在精神病院里的一个小事实，
never deterred you, not Scoop Caulfield!
从来没有吓到过你，不是Scoop Caulfield！
Now, most reporters are like me. They are plodders.
现在，大多数记者都像我一样。他们是笨蛋。
They spend a lot of their time checking little things..., like facts.
他们花了很多时间检查小事......就像事实一样。
They cover mundane stories like wars,
它们涵盖了战争，
and trials and hearings.
审判和听证等世俗故事。
You never seem to have enough time in your busy schedule
在忙碌的日程中
to stoop so low as to cover a story.
，你似乎没有足够的时间来弯腰以至于无法掩盖一个故事。
You occupy your time with tips from people who never existed,
你可以从那些从未存在过的人那里获取技巧，
driving your car into water and then claiming it wasn't your fault,
将你的车开入水中然后声称这不是你的错，
getting shot at by unseen gunmen.
被看不见的枪手射杀。
Now, I really hate to interrupt your meteoric career
现在，我真的很讨厌以
with something so plebeian as a legitimate story.
一种如此平凡的合法故事打断你的流星生涯。
However,
然而，
a trainload of propane gas had the bad taste
一连串的丙烷气体
to derail near Galveston and there's a whole town that just might blow up.
在加尔维斯顿附近出现了不好的味道，并且整个城镇可能会爆炸。
So it would be just really peachy or you
所以，
if you would join you film crew that's waiting for you on the plane
如果你愿意和我一起参加你在飞机
at this very moment while we speak.
上等待你的电影工作人员，那我们说话的时候真是太好了。
That was a speech. I thought so.
那是一个演讲。我是这么想的。
I cannot go to Galveston right now.
我现在不能去加尔维斯顿。
I don't think I heard you.
我不认为我听到了你。
Look,
看，
when a reporter tells his Assignment Editor
当记者告诉他的任务编辑时
that he thinks he may be onto something that could be really big,
，他认为他可能会做一些可能非常大的事情，
the Assignment Editor's suppose to say,
作业编辑假设说，
'You got forty-eight hours, kid,
'你有四十八个小时，孩子，
and you better come up with something good
你最好拿出一些好东西，
or it's gonna be your neck.'
或者它会成为你的脖子。
That's what he's supposed to say! I saw it in a movie!
这就是他应该说的！我在电影里看到了它！
Get your ass on that plane!
在那架飞机上得到你的屁股！
I can't! I have to follow this!
我不能！我必须遵循这个！
And you can't tell me what this earth-shattering story is?
你不能告诉我这个惊天动地的故事是什么？
It sounds too crazy. If I told you, I'd be in more trouble.
听起来太疯狂了。如果我告诉你，我会遇到麻烦。
You're not crazy! I'm crazy! I'm crazy for listening!
你不是疯了！我疯了！我很难听！
And I'm crazy for saying what I'm about to say!
而且我很想说我要说的话！
I'll give you twenty-four hours come up with something!
我会给你二十四小时的东西！
Not forty-eight! I saw the movie, too, and it was twenty-four!
不是四十八岁！我也看过电影，那是二十四岁！
Freeze!
冻结！
I'm not moving an inch. Robert Caulfield?
一世'?我不动一寸。罗伯特考菲尔德？
Yeah, who the hell are you? Federal Agents.
是的，你到底是谁？联邦特工。
We have a warrant to search your apartment.
我们有权搜查您的公寓。
You have a warrant? What for? Just don't move.
你有权证吗？做什么的？只是不要动。
I promise. Just tell me what this is all about.
我承诺。告诉我这是什么。
Hey, come here! Look at this!
嘿，过来！看这个！
Could you come with me, please, Mr. Caulfield?
考希尔德先生，请你跟我来吗？
Mr. Caulfield, I'm sorry.
考尔菲尔德先生，对不起。
However, you're under arrest for possession of cocaine.
但是，你因藏有可卡因而被捕。
I don't believe it.
我不相信。
I don't believe it. You guys put it there, you know you did.
我不相信。你们把它放在那里，你知道你做到了。
You have the right to remain silent.
你有保持沉默的权利。
You have the right to an attorney. I don't believe it. You put it there.
您有权获得律师。我不相信。你把它放在那里。
Anything you say may be held against you in a court of law.
你说的任何话都可能在法庭上对你不利。
You're part of all this. You mothers.
你是这一切的一部分。你妈妈?
Ow, that hurts!
喔，那很疼！
You don't have to put handcuffs on me!
你不必把手铐放在我身上！
Please, Mr. Caulfield, these are serious charges against you.
请考虑先生，这些是对你的严重指控。
Don't add to them by resisting arrest. I don't bel...! That hurts!
不要通过抵制逮捕来增加它们。我不喜欢......！那伤害了！
I don't believe this.
我不相信这一点。
Well, hello there, Caulfield! So nice to see you!
好吧，你好，Caulfield！很高兴见到你！
It's at this point that Alan Hale says to Richard Conte...
正是在这一点上，艾伦黑尔对理查德孔蒂说...?
Jimmy Stewart. Yeah, Jimmy Stewart, thank you.
吉米斯图尔特。是的，吉米斯图尔特，谢谢你。
Look, Scoop, I can't keep bailing you out of trouble.
看，Scoop，我不能让你摆脱困境。
The front office is on my neck.
前厅在我的脖子上。
I don't know how much longer I can keep them off, right?
我不知道能把它们关掉多久，对吧？
Right. Wrong!
对。错误！
I got you out of there so as not to embarrass the Network.
我让你离开那里，以免让网络难堪。
I mean, you are a schmuck! I can't trust you to cover a fire!
我的意思是，你是个笨蛋！我不能相信你掩盖火灾！
You'll probably fall down and get burned!
你可能会摔倒并被烧伤！
You probably would be the cause of it!
你可能会成为它的原因！
A company car? You are fired!
公司的车？你被开除了！
I love that so much! I'm gonna say it again!
我非常喜欢这个！我要再说一遍了！
You're fired! You're through! Oh, I love it!
你被开除了！你通过了！哦，我喜欢它！
It's not what it looks like, really.
真的，它不是它的样子。
'Frankly, Scarlet, I don't give a damn!'
“坦率地说，斯卡雷特，我不会诅咒！”?
I told you. You tell me about the lonely plight of a dedicated journalist.
我告诉你了。你告诉我一位专职记者的孤独困境。
I tell you to stuff it.
我告诉你这件事。
You tell me about a meaningful relationship.
你告诉我一段有意义的关系。
I tell you to stuff it.
我告诉你这件事。
You tell me you're in trouble, you're out on bail,
你告诉我你有困难，你被保释，
you just got fired, I tell you I'll be right over.
你被解雇了，我告诉你我会马上结束。
My head hurts. You look awful.
我头疼。你看起来很可怕。
Thank you, very much. You're quite welcome.
非常感谢你。你太客气了。
Did you find out what I asked?
你知道我问了什么吗？
One o'clock in the morning I get a call from an unemployed junkie
凌晨一点钟，我接到一名失业的瘾君子打来电话
to find out all the military installations in a 300 miles radius
，找出
around Houston, Texas.
德克萨斯州休斯顿周围300英里范围内的所有军事设施。
You certainly have a way with words. Did you find out?
你当然有办法说文字。你知道了吗？
Yes, and it wasn't easy. It took exhaustive research.
是的，这并不容易。它进行了详尽的研究。
Well, I'm proud of you. How many?
好吧，我为你感到骄傲。多少？
One. White Bluff. It's a S AC base. My father used to be stationed there.
一。白崖。这是一个S AC基地。我父亲曾经驻扎在那里。
That's exhaustive research?
这是详尽的研究？
At one o'clock in the morning, you call your father, that's exhaustive.
在凌晨一点，你打电话给你的父亲，这是详尽无遗的。
White Bluff... That's too big. Too big for what?
怀特布拉夫......那太大了。什么太大了？
Too big for what I want. What do you want?
太大了我想要的东西。你想要什么？
I'm thinking of enlisting.
我想要招募。
They'll never take you. That's why I'm thinking of enlisting.
他们永远不会带你。这就是我想要招募的原因。
You're on a story, aren't you? I was fired!
你是故事，不是吗？我被解雇！
You're on a story and I'm helping you. This can't be happening.
你是一个故事，我在帮助你。这不可能发生。
I really appreciate that.
我真的很感激。
The only reason I'm doing it, considering your track record,
我这样做的唯一原因，考虑到你的记录，
whatever story you're on will turn out to be garbage.
无论你在哪个故事，都会变成垃圾。
You shouldn't mince words.
你不应该贬低言辞。
I'll fix you some coffee. Then you can jump me.
我会给你一些咖啡。然后你可以跳我。
There's no other one besides White Bluff?
除了怀特布拉夫之外别无他人？
No.
没有。
Except one abandoned base they used for training
除了他们
during World War II, Jackson. There's nothing there now.
在第二次世界大战期间用于训练的一个废弃基地，杰克逊。现在什么也没有。
Don't you want to jump me? Of course I do. Where's Jackson?
你不想跳我吗？我当然是了。杰克逊在哪里？
About 300 miles directly West. I think I'm gonna get angry with you.
直接向西约300英里。我想我会生你的气。
Do you have any money on you? Do you want me to pay you?
你有钱吗？你要我付钱吗？
How much?
多少？
About 100. Why don't I just leave it on the dresser in the morning?
大概100.为什么我早上不把它放在梳妆台上？
Give it to me now.
现在把它给我。
In advance? That's the height of conceit!
提前？那是自负的高度！
Please, and your car keys.
请和你的车钥匙。
You're really being terrific, why?
你真的太棒了，为什么？
You're not as obnoxious when you are helpless.
当你无助时，你并不那么讨厌。
Thank you very much. You're quite welcome.
非常感谢你。你太客气了。
Also, Liz Haller said you were super.
此外，Liz Haller说你很超级。
Well, when I get back, we'll jump each other.
好吧，当我回来时，我们会相互跳跃。
Maybe.
也许。
I'll get arrested again.
我会再次被捕。
It's a deal.
就这么说定咯。
Mornin'.
清晨。
Mornin'. You in charge here?
清晨。你在这里负责？
You see that sign there? Yes.
你在那看到那个标志？是。
Well, read it.
好吧，看看吧。
I did. Out loud!
我做到了。响亮地！
'A and A Crop Dusting Service'.
'A和A作物除尘服务'。
You wanna know who I am?
你想知道我是谁吗？
I'll bet you're one of the 'A's.
我敢打赌你是'A'之一。
Well, which one? I'll bet you can't answer that question, smart-ass!
那么，哪一个？我打赌你不能回答这个问题，聪明屁股！
The first one. Wrong!
第一个。错误！
Can I have one more guess? You got it.
我可以再猜一次吗？你说对了。
The second one.
第二个。
Wrong. I'm both of 'em! 'A' and 'A'. My name is Albain.
错误。我是他们两个！'A'和'A'。我叫Albain。
I got a son. The other 'A' was for him, but he don't like to fly and is a lawyer.
我有一个儿子。另一个'A'适合他，但他不喜欢飞行并且是律师。
He's a pervert, so I took the 'A' away.
他是一个变态者，所以我把'A'拿走了。
Wanna speak to somebody in charge? You're speakin' to both o' them.
想和负责人谈谈吗？你跟他们说话了。
My name is Caulfield. Hey, I can't help that.
我叫考菲尔德。嘿，我忍不住了。
Mr. Albain, how much do you charge to dust a field?
阿尔班先生，你收取多少粉尘？
25 dollars. I'd like to hire your plane.
25美元。我想租你的飞机。
That'll be 100 dollars. You said you charged 25.
这将是100美元。你说你收费25。
25 dollars t' dust a field, but you ain't got no field because you ain't a farmer,
25美元
which means you ain't poor and I think you're a pervert!
为一片土地撒了一块灰尘，但你不是因为你不是农民而没有田地，这意味着你不是穷人，我认为你是一个变态者！
Okay, 100.
好的，100。125?
125 What?
什么？
Because you said 'yes' to 100 too quick,
因为你过快地对'100'说'是'，
which means you can afford 125!
这意味着你买得起125！
Where do you wanna go, smart-ass?
你想去哪里，智能屁股？
I'm not sure. I'm looking for someone who's lost.
我不确定。我在找一个迷路的人。
It's your money.
这是你的钱。
Put your Goddamn head down so I can see!
把你该死的头放下，这样我才能看到！
Why didn't you sit in front?
你为什么不坐在前面？
You know how to fly? No!
你知道怎么飞吗？没有！
Then I gotta sit in back
然后我必须坐在后面
and you gotta put your Goddamn head down, smart-ass!
，你必须把你的该死的头放下来，聪明的屁股！
Now, what the hell is your friend doin' out here?
现在，你的朋友到底在这里干什么？
He's lost!
他输了！
He rob a bank or somethin'? No!
他抢劫一家银行还是一些东西？没有！
Well, I get a third! What?
好吧，我得到了第三个！什么？
We find him, I get a third of the loot!
我们找到了他，我得到了战利品的三分之一！
Now, keep your Goddamn head down!
现在，保持你的该死的头！
You think we should go in another direction?
你认为我们应该走另一个方向吗？
Hey! What?
嘿!?什么？
Over there! Where?
在那边！哪里？
Helicopters!
直升机！
I seen them fly around here last couple of days!
我看到他们在这里飞了几天！
Let's follow 'em! I would if I could see 'em!
让我们跟着他们！如果我能看到他们，我会的！
They're goin' down over there!
他们在那边打瞌睡！
He must be in there!
他必须在那里！
Let's go down.
我们走下去吧。
They got guns, Sonny!
他们有枪，桑尼！
You said you wanted a third of the loot!
你说你想要三分之一的战利品！
Half! Okay, half!
半！好的，一半！
Keep your Goddamn head down!
保持你该死的头！
Pull that lever down by your feet when I tell you, Sonny!
桑尼，我告诉你，把你的脚拉下来吧！
Now!
现在！
Perverts!
变态！
Remember, I get half!
记住，我得到了一半！
Ladies and gentlemen,
女士们先生们，
Mrs. Brubaker
布鲁巴克
Mrs. Willis, Mrs. Walker,
太太，威利斯太太，沃克太太，
my fellow Americans.
我的美国同胞。
I come here today to talk of unfinished hopes
我今天来到这里谈论未完成的希望
and of unfulfilled dreams.
和未实现的梦想。
Charles Brubaker, Peter Willis and John Walker
查尔斯布鲁贝克，彼得威利斯和约翰沃克
left this Earth for their dream a little more than eight months ago.
在八个多月前离开这个地球是为了他们的梦想。
They were never able to return to us.
他们永远无法回到我们身边。?在愤世嫉俗是一种全国性流行病的时候，
Their dream was able to grow and flourish
他们的梦想得以蓬勃发展，
because of the support of millions of citizens
因为
all across America
全世界数百万公民的支持
at a time when cynicism was a national epidemic,
，
they gave us something to take pride in.
他们给了我们一些值得骄傲的东西。
It is a dream that should not be allowed to die.
这是一个不应该被允许死的梦想。
A nation is built on the spirit of its people.
一个国家建立在人民的精神之上。
The test of the greatness of any nation
对任何国家伟大的考验
is how that nation pulls together in a time of crisis.
这个国家是如何在危机时刻团结起来的。
The only limits on what we can achieve
我们能够实现的唯一限制是我们
are the limits we place on our hopes.
对希望的限制。
These three men reminded us of the limitlessness of our hopes.
这三个人提醒我们，我们的希望是无限的。
There was a moment in these past few days
过去几天
when we were all one people.
，我们都是一个人，有片刻。
We were all hoping,
我们都希望，
we were all a little bit taller,
我们都高
a little bit prouder.
一点，有点自豪。
We were all feeling the same fears and the same exhilaration.
我们都感受到同样的恐惧和同样的兴奋。
These three men brought us together.
这三个人把我们聚集在一起。
We knew together that there are no goals we cannot reach
我们一起知道，
if just reach for them together.
如果只是一起达成共识，就没有我们无法达到的目标。?我们
There is no adequate way
没有足够的方式
in which we can express our gratitude to the men themselves
表达对男人自己的感激之情，
because they are no longer among us.
因为他们不再在我们中间。
However, we can serve their memory,
然而，我们可以为他们的记忆服务，
what they stood for...
他们代表的是什么......?
Subtitle by B.Z. Studio
BZ Studio的副标题